Otter No. 11
Otter Human Meeting!
It's Spring.
I want to be in love.
Rie-chan you're too straightforward.
What's wrong in being straightforward?
Don't you want to be in love, Naho?
Of course I want!
I envy Emi-chan for having a boyfriend.
Well, that's not my preference.
I hope I find a wonderful lover somewhere.
Here he is.
Are you hurt?
Hey you! Naho!
Watch where you're walking, dumb morons.
Wait!
Oh my shoulder hurts.
It's a compound fracture.
But we hit your left shoulder...
Compensation is 1 million.
Pay it!
I don't carry such an amount.
Don't mess with me.
Stop it.
What?
You prowler!
Stay away from the ladies.
W-What you—
I'm but a normal Salaryman passing by.
Liar!
You're wearing a strange Headdress.
You're the prowler.
This is not a headdress.
I'm just a Salaryman who has an otter face.
Otter 11.
O-Otter 11!
Hey what is this?
Decide clearly, are you an otter or a human?
That's halfway.
Halfway?
What's wrong in being halfway?
Horsefly
Wasp
It's vague which to stay away from.
Day 1
Whatever done is left unfinished.
Day 2
Day 3
Deficit Bond
Trillion Yen
If it turns out bad leave immediately.
This world is charming because halfway people exist.
Halfway is rough on evil.
OLIVINE THOLEIITE
I hit a petty thing again.
Otter, the animal that smashes shells with rocks.
That beast's blood runs in my veins.
Excuse me?
Thanks for rescuing us from danger.
Thank you.
It's okay.
And—
I don't know how to thank you, but please accept this.
Rie-chan!
Naho-chan!
Good Morning!
Emi-chan!
Good Morning.
Lovely mood since morning!
I'm Otter Human.
Even if my face is otter.
As a human...
A clam is unacceptable!
La La La
Otter Otter Otter Otter
Otter Otter Otter No. 11
No. 1  has a little long beard
No. 2  has a good fur
No. 3  has big ears No. 4  has big chest
No. 5  has charming eyes
No. 6  has tried manicure
No. 7  has tried pedicure
No. 8 & 9  have no records
No. 10  has a 2-meters tail
And No. 11 We are No. 11
Otter Otter Otter Otter
Otter Otter Otter No. 11
Favorite beefsteak well-done