All right! The fifth chapter's all set now.
So let's have our meeting about the plot of the seventh chapter.
Okay.
What's with you guys?
Are you that worried about your second chapter getting 8th place?
Not really 'worried'...
more like if we look at
Baked Cheese's rankings,
it's quite possible that our third chapter will fall into a double-digit ranking as well.
Double-digits...
Hey now, guys.
You need to have more confidence!
Even though Cheese is in 12th place, it isn't getting canceled!
You guys are fine!
Are you completely sure?
Well, I can't say that with 100% certainty,
but as long as you don't fall to 18th or 19th place, I'm 99% sure!
If you aren't 100% sure,
you aren't completely sure!
There's no "100%" in this world!
Quit making a fuss!
But you're...
But if four new titles get serialized,
then everything below
15th place is in danger...
What is it with you two?
Manuscript #5 UP
Manuscript #6 UP
#7 Meeting
#8 Meeting
#7 Name Work
Assistant IN
Trap will definitely be fine!
More importantly, let's have our meeting about the next chapter.
Okay.
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream.
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Support and Patience
Good morning!
You too.
I left the early results on your desk.
Ah, yes.
Thank you.
The third chapter is in 9th place!
See? It only fell one ranking!
It looks like Trap will
continue, doesn't it?
Yeah! It's great!
Both Ashirogi Mutou and Niizuma are doing this while still in high school...
They're really something.
I think so too.
Of course, Niizuma graduated this spring.
"9th place is great!" he says.
Oh, that's right.
What do you think?
If you can change it, I think you should.
Our third chapter got 9th place.
Miura said it's okay, but...
With this story, it takes three
chapters to resolve a case.
The next serialization meeting is in two days, and I don't think we'll be canceled, but...
I don't know what will happen when the next results come in.
But if we don't have a certain amount of buildup in the story,
it won't be good reading as a mystery.
Yeah.
And Miura said we should just keep going with what we're doing now.
We'll be fine as long as our issues sell.
That's still a ways off.
And I don't think it'll sell well with the ranking it's got now.
I don't think so, either.
You shouldn't just
believe what Miura says.
I was a finalist for the Tezuka Award and Miura picked me up, but...
He said "This'll be fine!" and I turned in three different manuscripts...
but none of them even
got the monthly prize.
I don't want to say anything
bad about someone
who's willing to take
on challenging projects,
but he doesn't have much experience and he's way too optimistic.
So I'm just trying to submit
works that I think are good.
Won't it be bad if I just change the name without consulting him?
You're the one who's
ultimately in charge of the plot.
I'll draw whatever you feel is best.
With that, we have to show Miura the name two days from now.
I have to pen-in the sixth chapter, so I don't have much time for major changes.
Yes?
Just a moment.
Sensei, Hiramaru is here.
Oh, it's Hiramaru-sensei!
Please tell him to wait. I'll be right there.
Click.
Niizuma! Hide me please!
Are you being chased by bad people?
More like the police.
I respect all mangakas.
19 pages, week after week.
It isn't human!
Aren't you doing it too?
I'm at my limit already.
Working at a normal
company was 100 times better.
It suits me more.
I was happy having weekends off.
My editor says you can't do this kind of work unless you like it.
I like it, so it's fun for me.
That must be how it is.
I don't really like manga,
so it's hard to do it as a career.
If you want to quit, just talk to the chief editor. I'm sure he'll cancel it for you.
Huh? It can be stopped?
This is Yoshida from Yueisha.
It's Yoshida-shi!
Hiramaru!
I know you're in there!
Come out quietly!
Whoa, he really is like the police.
How did he know I was here?!
I called him!
Y-You!
You're annoying!
When I look at you, I get
really pissed off, y'know!
We're betting our careers as mangakas on the serialization meeting two days from now!
So what the hell are you
going on about here?
Don't screw with me!
S-Sorry!
What should I do?
All you have to do is draw manga.
Hiramaru's kind of pitiful, don't you think?
Not at all!
Even though we know it won't get canceled,
it sucks waiting for that phone call on the day of the serialization meeting.
Shut up and ink.
What's with that?
You're always telling me to talk more and liven things up.
Shut up.
Eh, already?
Isn't it early this time?
Hi, this is Mashiro.
Oh, Mashiro?
Trap is fine, like I told you.
Thank you.
Two new serializations have
been decided on this time.
Yes!
Finally, my time has come!
I did it!
This is great!
Both of you are serialized!
Double Congratulations!
Thank you, thank you!
I'm finally serialized with Aoki...
it feels so good to be alive!
But you two can't
work with me anymore...
I'm kind of sad.
Don't be ridiculous.
We'll be serialized in Jack together!
There's nothing better than that!
Take down Crow!
No, take down every other manga!
I won't lose to Kiyoshi or Door.
Bring it on, guys.
Yeah!
I won't lose, either!
Both Aoki and I!
I see...
Yes.
Both Kiyoshi Knight and
Hideout Door at once, huh?
Awesome.
This is bad.
The "Golden Future Cup."
In the last serialization meeting,
those were the works we
were competing against.
I'm sure they reworked them and brought them back to the table.
And the ones that are
ending are Takano's Chain Gold...
and Arai's Baked Cheese.
Eh? Baked Cheese is canceled?
That was fast!
Even though Cheese is in 12th place, it isn't getting canceled!
You guys are fine!
Saiko.
Um, Miura, can you hold on for a minute?
What is it, Shuujin?
I'm going to change chapter seven's name right now!
Change, you say?
Our third chapter was at 9th place...
at this rate, we're finished!
Our goal is for an anime production, right?
With our ranking right now, we can't...
Th-That's right...
An anime, huh.
Well, with a Jack serialization, anyone would think about that.
I don't want to lose to
Kiyoshi Knight or Hideout Door.
And of course, not to
Crow or Otters 11 either!
Me either!
I don't want to lose!
Then let's redo the name!
Miura, this is Takagi.
Oh, Takagi.
Sorry for keeping you waiting.
I know, really.
So what's up?
Have you finished
chapter seven's name?
Um, I need to ask you
something about that.
Actually...
What?! You want to change the name?!
What are you talking about?
You said you'd show it to me today!
You have to draw it according to our arrangement at the meeting!
No, I don't think things
will go well like this.
Let's have another meeting!
Another one?!
Anyway, it's tough for me to talk here.
I'll call you from my cell.
Geez, what is he thinking?
What's wrong?
Ah, nothing.
Oh right, Aida.
Trap wasn't brought up as a candidate for cancellation in today's meeting, was it?
Nope, not this time.
It might be in danger by
the next meeting, though.
If it keeps falling, I don't know what'll happen in two months.
That's...
It's your job to make sure it doesn't come up as a candidate for cancellation!
You'd better discuss this
throughly with the authors.
But... the direction Trap is
taking isn't wrong, correct?
Yeah.
I think the classic mystery approach is good.
I know, right?!
If that doesn't work out, oh well.
Oh well?
Oops, I have to call them.
Sorry I kept you waiting.
It's fine.
Can we continue this conversation tomorrow when I come to pick up the manuscript?
Tomorrow?
I'd like to talk about it before then, but...
I understand.
Tomorrow, chapter six's
manuscript will be finished
and Mashiro will have time for a meeting.
Okay.
I'll also bring the name
we already agreed on.
All right. See you tomorrow.
Why are you sighing, Miura?
Well, it's about Trap...
They want to change the
name all of a sudden.
Well, they did get a mediocre ranking.
Mediocre?
Do you really think so?
Getting 9th place on your
third chapter isn't that great.
I'd support them on this.
There's no way those two would be satisfied with 9th place.
Obviously, they're going to aim higher!
Um, how exactly should I support them?
How should I know?
You're their editor.
Miura, you'd be better
off not supporting them.
Trap is the kind of manga that'll get more popular on it's own, slowly but surely.
T-That's right!
No, he should help them out.
A mystery will never be popular in Jack!
It should set up an interesting mystery and tricks, no matter how many chapters that takes.
If they do that, it'll definitely get popular.
How about seeing how it goes if you resolve mysteries in one chapter?
No, if you do that, the tricks will be cheap.
You should build it up
slowly over many chapters.
And I've been saying that kind of mystery isn't suited for Jack!
H-Hey everybody, stop
saying different things!
I'll get even more confused!
Anyways, with a double-digit ranking they won't be able to keep it going.
What is Miura doing?
He's worried about the
direction Trap should be taking.
That's bad, isn't it?
The longer it runs, the more popular it'll get.
If the editor's in this state, he isn't going to get good results from his authors.
Heishi, go over there.
But most manga get canceled before they reach that point.
Yes, sir.
Hey, don't get full of yourself just because Crow's popular!
Yoshida, you shouldn't go thinking that you're right all the time either,
just because Otters 11
got a good reception!
Hey, hey...
Hey, this is about the gap!
Wait, why am I trying to
smooth things over here?
That has nothing to do with this!
That's enough, all of you.
Sorry, we just...
Have more confidence in yourself, Miura!
Y-Yes sir.
Listen, don't have that kind of attitude in front of the authors.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Furthermore, Yoshida and Yuujirou shouldn't butt in on other people's manga!
Come on, back to work.
Yeah.
Which is it?
I have until tomorrow to decide on my opinion as their editor.
Support them, huh?
Those two should be all right as long as they don't rush into a decision...
Well, we'll be leaving now.
Have a good evening!
Good work today!
Hey, aren't you guys gonna call Fukuda to congratulate him?
We should do that to be polite,
but I'm not in the mood for it with all this worrying about chapter seven.
But they called you
when you got serialized!
They might be busy with
their new serialization too.
Huh?
She's right.
The least we could do is make a short call.
Right, right.
Try it, but hang up if they're too busy.
Oh, thanks, Mashiro!
You didn't have to call.
Yeah, if I failed this time,
I was gonna knock Yuujirou out.
Trap's been having a
difficult time though, right?
You okay?
A difficult time...
it does seem that way after all.
Hello? I'm giving the phone to Nakai.
Oh, okay.
Hey Mashiro!
Thanks a lot!
Even though I'm past 30,
I'll be in your care.
Uh, yeah. Let's try our best together.
By the way, I'm about to go
meet up with Aoki now.
R-Right.
This moment has finally come.
We're going to change Jack.
Everyone who talked about
that has become serialized!
Yes.
We're going to change Jack...
But as it is now, Trap will...!
Ashirogi-sensei!
Eiji!
Shady Detective Trap is really interesting!
It's good to differentiate
from Jack's normal stuff.
The stories that Takagi
makes are really well done.
I'm surprised!
Ah, thank you.
Eiji said your stories were well done.
Of course they are, right?
If Eiji says that from his 3rd place ranking,
I can't hear it as anything but sarcasm.
Hey, hey.
Anyways, how should I change
the seventh chapter?
For it to be popular, I suppose I have put in some kind of battle...
It's good to differentiate from Jack's normal stuff.
What does that mean?
Shady Detective Trap
Serialization Name Chapter 5
I just fleshed out an idea I had...
Okay.
What do you think?
Does it look like good material?
If we were to go in a "Jack-like" direction, it would be this, I guess.
I reread popular manga all night and came up with some new material.
I was planning on refining it a bit more for tonight's meeting.
And we have to think of
a way to persuade Miura.
Well, I'll figure something out.
Yeah, you're right.
It's as we discussed before...
no, it's even better.
I think this is good.
I've prepared some ideas
on how to change it—
No need for that.
You haven't even seen them!
We want to improve our ranking!
Don't be so presumptuous.
Your final ranking was also 9th.
That's good enough.
If you make a bad move, you'll fail.
B-But...
Instead of aiming higher, right now you should be aiming to keep 9th place.
What's with that?!
That's not right!
Shouldn't we always be
trying to aim higher?!
Trap isn't that kind of manga!
Miura...
Right now, you need to have patience.
You have to let the mystery
get firmly established.
I don't think that's true.
I feel our ranking will drop at this rate—
It's okay for it to drop a bit!
Don't freak out!
I have one suggestion.
What is it?
Will you stop paying
attention to survey results?
This is only my second year on the job,
but I've seen so many new guys fail because they worried too much about the results.
Originally, the ranking wasn't something we told authors.
But once they learned about the rankings,
they'd naturally want to hear the results.
O-Of course!
It worries us, and it's normal to refer to your past results going forward—
That's what I thought
up until yesterday.
But it's tough to have the
rankings thrown in your face.
That's why you're talking about changing the plot over a 9th place ranking.
He's right...
It may be better to do it without knowing the survey results.
Miura!
You said chapter seven is fine as is,
but does that mean you
think it will be popular?
I don't think so.
Shady Detective Trap
Serialization Name Chapter 7
Don't screw with us!
Then I should change it!
I don't think it'll be popular,
but I don't think it'll drop much either.
If you change the story now,
you destroy yourselves.
You'll just hasten your cancellation.
You're saying that right now we're just staving off cancellation by the skin of our teeth!
That's true in a way.
Once you're serialized, you just have to keep it going one chapter at a time.
That's why this plot is fine.
Just add one chapter at a time the way you're doing now!
That's the best thing for
this manga and for you!
Takahama said that he seems like a guy who can't do anything,
but he's looking at Trap
more calmly than we are.
But manga is a gamble!
We have to put something on the line and aim for the top!
It's better to fail doing that
than to do nothing at all!
No, that's wrong.
We need to go forward like this.
Even if it ends like this!
"If it ends?"
What are you saying?!
Saiko, you say something too!
Manga is a gamble.
Hey, Saiko! Are you listening?
Will we win?
Or not?
Our first chapter was 3rd place.
Second was 8th.
Third was 9th.
Is it a winner or a loser?
Shady Detective Trap is really interesting!
It's good to differentiate
from Jack's normal stuff.
I think Miura is right.
And suddenly, you're
changing your mind too?!
Being a mangaka is a gamble,
but after you're serialized, maybe it isn't.
Well, even if it is, what Shuujin's doing is...
desperate.
Whether it's a gamble or not, if we're desperate, we lose.
Saiko, I don't get what you're saying!
The stories you make are good!
Yeah, they're good!
Last night I read chapters one through six over and over again.
They're still really good!
Eiji said yesterday that it's good to differentiate from Jack's normal stuff.
That was praise, after all!
It's fine for a genuine mystery manga to be different from Jack's normal stuff!
In other magazines, this type of story is successful with readers.
We just need to let them know...
that there's a genuine
mystery manga in Jack!
We have to pull the people who like that type of manga in!
Saiko...
If we're going to gamble on Trap,
I'd rather continue with our style till the end and gather fans.
Your stories can do that!
I get it.
I'll try my hardest
with our current style.
Hello, hello. It's Mecha. Mecha Crow!
Oh, Ashirogi-sensei?
What's up?
I wanted to thank you.
Thank me?
Yes.
Actually, we were confused as to what direction to take Trap forward.
What were you confused about?
It's good as is.
Yeah. It's good.
Your words saved us!
I see.
Hiramaru, you said the same thing last week, it'll be fine.
It looks like you persuaded them to take Trap in the direction of a genuine mystery.
Yeah.
All right, I'm coming now.
But really, it was Mashiro who
said what I wanted to say.
Well, at any rate, everything worked out.
Yeah!
I thought he'd say that they decided to take the easy road and turn it into a battle manga, but...
they've both grown.
But it will certainly be
dangerous from now on.
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
Next
Episode
I hope Trap gets popular!
But it may not be that suited for Jack.
You think so?
I mean, I want it to continue, of course.
Comedy and
News
Next time on Bakuman:
Comedy and News.
I think it's good!