juurai karametorareteku wana ni
Before, caught in a trap,
shikakerareta omoi wo sagashite
I search for the tricked feelings
Shady Detective
mayoikomi mou deguchi sae ushinatte
Lost, unable to find even the exit anymore
imi sae mo utagau sekai
A world where even meanings are questioned
doko ni aru no
Where is it
Trick or truth. dochira wo erabu?
Trick or truth. Choose either one?
tobira no kagi wa
The key to the door is
Fake makes truth. kimeta nara
Fake makes truth. Once decided
ima uso de migaida naifu yami wo kirisake
The knife polished by lies will now cut through darkness
juurai egakidasareteku koko ni
Trap! It’s drawn here
shinjitsu ga sono sugata kakushitemo
Even if truth hides that form
You find! tashikana kotae no shouko wa
You find! The proof of the right answer
kimi ga tsukuru! ahite wo hiraku kagi wo
You make it! The key that opens tomorrow