Kaya is still 19.
I know.
Sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
You're always saying,
"No one will ever take an abrasive woman like you as a bride."
"If a guy like that exists,
I'd like to meet him."
You should be glad! This is him!
Just look at him! He's
pretty handsome, right?
Sorry.
He wants to be a mangaka, huh?
He already is one! He's
been serialized before!
And he's got a new
one starting in February.
Your friend was a
mangaka, wasn't he?
Don't bring that up now.
He literally put his life
on the line to draw manga,
and ended up dying because of it.
He died?
Was that friend of yours Kawaguchi Tarou, by any chance?
That's right.
Mashiro Nobuhiro.
His pen name was Kawaguchi Tarou.
He was
my best friend.
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Fate and Star
Shuujin's probably being
told something like
"I won't hand my daughter over to a mangaka with such an unstable future!" by now.
I see.
So you're working
with his nephew.
Y-Yes.
It's like fate, isn't it?
Can you call this
Mashiro Moritaka here?
Why?
If they're a team,
then I want to test the team's determination, not just Akito's.
Test their determination?
Shuujin!
Did it not work out after all?
What's up?
Saiko!
Team up with me for a karate match against Miyoshi's dad!
Huh?!
What are you on about?!
He wants to test our
determination as a team!
Please!
I've got nothing to do with this!
But you do!
Apparently, Miyoshi's dad and Kawaguchi Tarou were old friends!
Once that came to light, it seemed like things were looking up,
but then he said he wanted
to test our determination.
Okay.
I'll be right there.
There he is.
Mashiro!
Sorry to call you out
while you were working.
Sorry, Saiko.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Mashiro Moritaka.
You've grown.
I saw you briefly at the funeral.
Well, let's get to the dojo.
I-I'll try my best.
R-Right.
Hang in there, Akito...
Please take your time.
Um...
That karate match thing was just an excuse to get you two away.
Huh?
Some things are difficult to say in front of my wife and daughter.
Mashiro Nobuhiro.
Nobu was my best friend...
and my rival in love.
Rival in love?
Was it Haruno Miyuki?
How do you know about her?
Some letters from her were
left in my uncle's office.
We got a general idea from those.
I see.
The letters, huh?
Yakusa City Akehi
Middle School
Class of 1980
Graduation
Ceremony
Yakusa City Akehi Middle School
Hey, Nobu, why'd you
bring me out here?
You gonna confess your
love to me, or something?
Yosshi...
What, seriously?
I'll say this only to you.
Wait! Don't be too hasty!
I don't swing that way—
I just got a letter from Haruno.
What?!
But this isn't a love letter.
"Let's do our best in high school.",
just that.
She's just shy!
A girl as shy as her sending
you a letter is pretty much
the confession of a lifetime!
R-Really?
Definitely!
I'm super jealous,
but I'll be fine, since it's you.
Then can I write a reply?
Yeah, go for it!
I know the rest from
reading the letters.
In the end,
they never told each
other their feelings,
and Miyuki married someone else.
He was an idiot.
If he had just told her back then, who knows how things could've turned out?
Um...
What is it?
Miyuki's daughter went
to our middle school,
and she's dating
Mashiro right now!
And this girl...
well, her name's Azuki Miho.
She's Kaya's best friend.
Miho?
I hear Kaya talking about
her sometimes, but I didn't...
About that!
Her dream's been to become a voice actress ever since middle school.
Will Akito be okay?
If he gets a fracture,
he won't be able to
write manga anymore.
You don't need to worry.
But...
The karate thing was just an excuse.
Succeed as a mangaka,
then get married, huh?
You've done enough, haven't you?!
Why won't you tell her your feelings?!
I was just a bit lucky with
my current serialization!
Until I succeed as a mangaka
and can make a living...
Do you have to do all this
just to tell her how you feel?
Yeah!
Because I want to marry her!
If I date her,
then it'll be with the
intention of marriage.
I can't believe the nephew would take after his uncle so much.
I can't help but cheer you on too.
Cheer me on...
Then...
Yeah.
After what happened with Nobu,
I think it's best to be with the person you love as soon as possible.
If people make an honest
effort, it'll work out.
You seem like an honest guy.
Thank you so very much!
You too.
Make your dream come true.
For Nobu's sake as well!
Yes!
I'll work hard for it!
I'm so glad her parents
were nice people.
I enjoyed learning
more about my uncle.
It's from Azuki.
Instead of replying
to me, she calls you?
Congratulations, Takagi!
Thanks!
I'll do my best so that you and Saiko can get married soon too!
Make sure to always get
along with Kaya and Mashiro!
And with you too.
Yeah, thanks!
I have to call Kaya.
I'm really happy for you two!
All right!
Let's go for it!
Let's make Tanto a big hit!
Yeah!
Because your lifestyle depends on it!
Don't say that!
The pressure's gonna kill me!
My bad!
Here, please take this ticket.
Th-Thanks.
Oh, you're here.
Miura.
Sorry, but I'm still
getting things ready.
Go on without me.
Okay.
Um...
Ashirogi!
Fukuda!
Aoki too!
Good evening.
I came too.
Of course.
There's no way you'd miss the New Year's party, Hiramaru.
That's true.
Hattori!
Oh, congrats on
your new serialization!
Well, enjoy the party.
O-Okay...
I'm Ibaraki, editor-in-chief of Jack SQ.
We're aware of
+NATURAL's reputation.
By the way,
if there are any other stories you'd like to write, by all means—
Akina!
Hattori!
I read your fax.
Chapter seven was well done.
Thank you.
Do you have any
questions or concerns?
If you do, I'll quickly—
No.
None at all. It was fantastic.
Enjoy yourself today.
Oh, the seventh
chapter was good too?
Yeah.
I'm so excited to read
what happens next!
Hattori, I want to read the
seventh chapter right away.
Sure.
Right after the party.
I'm looking forward to it!
I don't know much about it,
but there's some pretty
good hype for Natural.
Really?
Don't you think they're being kind of cold?
I was really surprised though!
You've shown some real talent by taking Akina Aiko's manuscript this far!
That's true,
but you're something else too.
You thought of having
Niizuma draw another manga.
Yes,
I'm happy to have a popular author in Jack draw it for me.
Indeed, Hattori is the rising star of the editorial department.
Oh, please.
Yes!
Hattori is a rising star!
A rising star?
Niizuma, will you really be
okay with five assistants?
No problem!
I'll be Jack's number
one author this year too!
It seems like the editorial department's
expecting a lot more from
Natural than Tanto!
Let's prove them wrong shall we?
I definitely don't
want to lose to Iwase.
Yeah.
This time we'll overtake Eiji!
Thank you for coming today.
Arai, what are you doing after this?
There are things we can't talk about while the editors are around.
Then let's go somewhere else.
Fukuda!
What are you talking
about with Aoki?
That's unfair!
Let's all go to the afterparty!
But Ashirogi and Master
Niizuma are still underage.
Akina too.
Then we can just go
to a family restaurant!
I'll get Niizuma-sensei.
Niizuma-sensei, let's go to a—
I need to get back to
work, so I'm going home.
Work?
I'm going to make a name
for the seventh chapter.
You've already done up
through to the third chapter,
there's no need to rush.
Right, right!
Forget about work for today!
No, I won't!
I'm having fun drawing
manga right now!
I could barely pull myself away from drawing to come here today!
Okay, I'll go grab it from
the editorial department.
Then, SEE YOU AGAIN!
Hmph, party-pooper.
Then how about the rest of us go—
Huh?
What?
All right.
They've all gone home.
Hiramaru, what are you
doing there all alone?
Yoshida-shi...
Niizuma
Eiji  Ltd.
Akira, you were too obvious.
What do you mean?
Giving Ashirogi that
much incentive...
Why are you backing
them so much?
Niizuma,
it isn't good practice to support authors one isn't in charge of.
If it looked like that to you,
please don't tell anyone else.
I know.
That's why I'm bringing it up now.
In the future, Ashirogi will become one of the pillars of Jack.
That's what I believe.
Just like you are.
I think so too,
and I want it to happen soon.
So no matter how you
support them, I'll help you!
However...
I won't lose to them!
Nice to meet you!
I'm Orihara Ichiriki!
Looking forward to working together!
Orihara got an honorable
mention for the Tezuka Prize.
I've got Takahama too, so
you guys should be all set.
I'm the artist, Mashiro.
I'm the writer, Takagi.
And I'm his wife, Takagi Kaya!
Nice to meet you!
H-Huh?
Wife?
They registered at
the end of last year.
You're a freshman in college with a serialization and a wife?!
Awesome!
Too awesome!
There really are a ton
of strange mangakas!
I'll do my best too!
The two of us will live
here from now on.
I'm so happy!
Your dad's giving us the
realtor hookup, huh?
Let's be happy.
Hm?
No, I'll make us happy.
Takagi
Okay!
All right!
The first chapter's done!
Good work, everybody.
Mashiro
I brought the publishing
sample of +NATURAL.
An opening color page?
And Crow's got one in the middle?
It's already a Niiuzma Eiji issue.
Well, he's drawing both of them.
They don't want people
to overlook either of them.
Anyway, let's check out Natural.
Yeah.
This is good!
It's not just good!
It's got an indie vibe.
And even though all the conventions of a first chapter are being broken,
it still feels mainstream!
Indie? Mainstream?
I don't get it.
It's not about defeating some enemy
and wrapping things
up in one chapter,
but you can definitely
tell it's a shounen manga.
Yeah.
He's following the pattern
of stuff like Pokémon
by hatching the egg into various monsters.
Oh, that I can understand.
That's super mainstream!
As for franchise opportunities,
if it were turned into a card game, kids would probably love it.
And an anime too.
Speaking of anime adaptations...
Otters 11 will be turned
into a late-night anime!
No way!
Not even I could lie about that.
Yoshida-shi!
I'm so glad I listened to you!
I've been a terrible
person for thinking of you
as a long-haired narcissistic con man who tricks me time and time again!
So that's how you think of me?
Well, not that you're wrong.
We'll announce it in
the magazine this spring.
The anime starts in the fall.
You understand,
don't you, Hiramaru?
Yes!
Until fall...
No, for the rest of the year, I won't breathe a word about taking a break!
By the way,
why a late-night slot?
I can't tell him that no
matter how long we wait,
we'll never get an offer
for an evening timeslot.
Right.
Well, you know, it has
a pretty dark theme.
I see!
This should be good for a while.
Oh I'm just too much!
Otters and Crow got an anime.
Fukuda and Aoki's look promising,
so if we don't pull out all the
stops, we'll be left behind.
The first chapter of Tanto has already been sent to the press.
The names up to chapter
three have been finalized.
The rest is out of our hands.
Oh, have you come up with
an idea for the invention
that'll appear in the fourth chapter?
Not yet...
I was going to wait for the results of the first chapter and revise it based on that.
Still,
you need to be brainstorming
ideas one after another.
Otherwise, you can't move forward.
You're right.
I'll make a list by tomorrow.
Welcome.
That'll be 250 yen.
Thank you very much.
Do you need a bag?
______Jack
Sold Out
Yes.
Okay then.
Here's your change: 10 yen.
Thank you. Please come again.
This is crazy!
This week's Jack
is completely sold out in every
convenience store and bookstore!
It's only 3 PM on a Monday!
Is it the Niizuma Eiji effect?!
No way.
It has to be a coincidence!
No, you're exactly right.
Everyone was buzzing about it on the Internet yesterday before it went on sale.
They were saying that
+NATURAL is going to be great!
News
New work by Niizuma Eiji a hot topic before it even goes on sale!
Entertainment: In next week's Shounen Jack, on sale on the 18th, +Natural will begin
serialization. This is a new work by popular mangaka Niizuma Eiji of Crow fame.
The manuscript is done by amateur novel contest winner, Akina Aiko.
Niizuma Eiji's "Crow" is also currently in serialization, meaning he will have
an unprecedented two simultaneous serializations in Jack!
From the moment it was announced in the magazine,
it's been a hot topic on the Internet, creating waves.
Outside Line
Options
Away
Silent
My apologies.
All copies were sold out yesterday.
It's first place in
the preliminary polls!
We did it!
And now for the final results...
It's first place by a long shot!
Crow's in fourth.
All that's changed since
it ranked third last week
is Natural being placed at the top.
It's perfect.
Natural is first place, after all?
I really don't want Tanto's
first chapter to rank under
Natural 's second chapter.
I know how you feel,
but plot-driven manga and
gag manga are different.
Anything in the top
three is a great success.
Even top five is great.
That doesn't matter.
Natural was first place.
Tanto will be first too!
Yeah!
We stopped by the
convenience store, but...
...there were a lot left this week.
Don't worry about that!
Last week was unusual!
By this time tomorrow...
No, by tonight, they'll all be gone!
It's Miura!
It must be the results!
You got fifth place!
Fifth...
Come on.
What's with that reaction?
I told you before that
getting fifth place with a
gag manga is a good thing!
Oh, yeah...
What about Natural?
Third?
Yes...
Crow was fourth.
I read Hirameki! Tanto-kun.
It'll definitely be a
big hit with the kids!
Kids...
Huh?
Hey, cheer up already.
You'll feel a lot better if
you move around some!
Huh?
Was there more stuff coming?
Coming!
Iwase!
Congratulations on your marriage.
How do you know where we live?
I called your parent's house.
I really just wanted
to congratulate you.
Thanks!
See ya.
Wait a minute!
"Just wanted to congratulate us?!"
Until a little while ago, you were saying you were in love with my man!
I read that letter!
Stop it!
But I can't take her
congratulations seriously!
I liked the Takagi with talent.
What the hell does that mean?!
Stop, I said!
Natural was more popular!
You have more talent than me!
Without a doubt!
That's what you wanted
to hear, right, Iwase?
Yes.
Take this back.
Ever since middle school,
Takagi Akito has only
had eyes for me.
I don't need your congratulations.
You should hurry up and find some other guy with more talent than him.
I already have.
Really?
Who is it?
You're just blowing hot air.
It's Hattori!
Your editor?!
He's your boyfriend?!
No...
But he's a man with great
talent that I can admire.
He's the man I like.
Your sixth chapter
came in 11th, as well.
Same as last week.
The first chapter was 5th,
the second was 9th,
the third was 10th,
and ever since then,
it's stayed at 11th place.
In a sense, it's stable.
Hey, guys, you should feel proud.
The lead editor even
said it's been a long time
since Jack had a manga that's well-received by the younger readers.
He did?
Yeah!
Kids usually pick
their top three manga
based on how funny they think it is, not the quality of the plot.
Gag manga have the advantage there.
I don't care about that!
We have to think about
how we can do better!
Better, huh?
How to pull in more kids?
Will Tanto become a boom,
or will Tanto start a boom?
A boom, a boom...
Starting a boom with a gag manga...
Some signature joke that
will stick in kids' heads...
Oh, that's it!
It may be a bit old, but
something like Iyami's "Shii!"
If you repeat the same joke over and over, it'll start a fad!
I can try for it,
but I don't know if I can do it.
I'll work at it.
If I have something repeatable,
it might make writing jokes easier.
I see.
We can get better rankings
if we change how we do things!
Good work.
The seventh chapter's
still at 2nd place...
Natural is really something.
Well, it's not like Crow
dropped in popularity.
It actually got more votes.
Speaking of rankings,
your favorite Ashirogi has
settled at 11th place.
The editorial department is saying things like, "Looks like Ashirogi can do gag manga too,"
and "Manga that bring in
younger readers are valuable."
What do you think of Tanto?
I'm not reading it
anymore!
What?!
toomawari wo eranda no wa
The reason I chose to take a detour
motto kimi wo suki ni naru tame datta n da
was to fall ever deeper in love with you
boku no namae yobu sono koe wo
I have a feeling I've always known
zutto zutto shitteta ki ga shita n da
what your voice sounds like when it calls my name
boku no yubisaki de egaita
With my fingertips I drew
subete no sen wa kimi ni tsuzuku kakehashi sa
many lines that make up a suspension bridge leading to you
(Show me the way) bokura no michi kitto
(Show me the way) I'm sure our path
(Believe in your way) hitosuji ni tsunagari
(Believe in your way) connects us without any turns
(Show me the way) yakusoku no basho e tsuzuku
(Show me the way) It leads to the place where we promised
(Show me the way) akirametari shinaide
(Show me the way) I will never give up
(Believe in your way) sono hitomi wo agete
(Believe in your way) Raise your gaze
(Show me the way) bokura wa massugu deau sa
(Show me the way) and see that we're certain to meet again
Next
Episode
Is it okay for us to
continue Tanto like this?
Don't say something so unnerving right before my wedding ceremony!
Next time on Bakuman:
Love and
Denial
"Love and Denial."
In order to achieve your dream,
you need to stick to your goals!