Kitashita Juuichi
Mashiro Moritaka
Mashiro, let's do our best.
I know you can draw without resting.
I believe in you.
Let's make our dreams come true.
Yeah.
I-I cant tell him to stop drawing.
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Life-and-Death and Standstill
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
Azuki.
Yes?
I'm all right now.
Oh, sorry.
T-Thanks.
Mashiro, Takagi.
I'll be frank.
The editorial department is
going ahead with their plans
to put you on hiatus with
chapter 20 in issue 33.
That's...!
I won't go on hiatus.
Ever!
All right.
That's what I'll tell them
when I get back to the office.
And I'll also tell them I think you can draw in the hospital.
Yes!
Please do!
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
Oh, it's already this late?
Saiko, don't push yourself too hard. Get some sleep, okay?
Yeah, I can't go to school, so I should be able to get some decent sleep.
Anyways, I think I can make a clean copy
of the rest of chapter
20's name by tomorrow.
No, you don't need to.
I can understand the story well enough from Takagi's version.
I'll work it out with Takagi
and make sure you can get started on the manuscript by Saturday, as usual.
Let's head out, then.
But there's still a bit
of time left, isn't there?
We might as well stay...
See ya.
Hey, whats with you?
Hurry, hurry.
Jeez, that Shuujin.
He did something he didn't need to.
I'll come every day I can.
Why?
Because I'm worried...
and I can't email you here.
Well, I can use my cell phone if I step outside the hospital...
I should be able to turn it on if I go out into the courtyard.
Everyone does it.
And I'll be fine.
You don't need to worry so much.
It may contradict what I said before,
but being able to see
you makes me happy.
Let's limit it to until you're
released from the hospital.
Can I keep coming?
Does it bother you?
I might also be contradicting myself.
When I'm with you,
I get embarrassed and
my heart starts pounding...
but it also calms me down.
I feel like I want us to
be together forever.
But only until I'm discharged.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Get well soon!
I'm glad I got sick.
It seems like I'll have some good memories of being here with you.
Mashiro.
Does it bother you that we decided to stay apart until our dreams come true?
It's not like that.
I think it's hard sometimes,
and after I get discharged it'll be hard to go back to being apart from you,
but that's exactly why I can push myself.
I want to see you soon.
I want to be with you.
Yeah.
I understand.
Until our dreams come true.
I'm saying I think he can still draw!
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
I don't want to force
them to go on hiatus!
What are you saying, Miura?
Well, we can at least put the bit that the assistants finish up into issue 32.
Thank you!
However, I will still put out the hiatus
announcement from issue 33 onwards.
B-But...
Are you telling me you received permission to let him draw from his doctor?
N-No...
I'll accompany you to
the hospital tomorrow.
It seems I can't count on
you to get the job done.
Yes sir...
The patient is saying
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
that if he is not allowed to draw, his stress will increase, and it will be bad for his health.
It is true that patients should be allowed to do as they like in moderation.
Really?
Only in moderation.
I won't push myself.
How about it?
Ah, sorry to barge in, ma'am.
This is the Editor in Chief—
It's been a while.
Thank you for taking care of my son.
You've met before?
It's not something
I should mention here.
We are to blame for the current situation,
and I offer my deepest apologies.
No, you aren't...
Moritaka!
Stop drawing manga
in your hospital room!
Ah, well, the doctor said
it was fine in moderation...
He won't be able to
do it "in moderation"!
Well, it isn't good to be too persistent.
I'll rest a bit.
Your name was Sasaki, correct?
I'd like to talk with you.
My husband said that
he's not a child anymore,
and to let him continue
on the path he chose.
But I just can't...
Rest assured, we will not
let any harm come to him.
Hiramaru Kazuya
No Mr.Yoshida
No
Soliciting
Mr. Yoshida...
I think I should go visit
Ashirogi in the hospital.
Where did you hear about that?
We tried to keep it quiet.
I won't reveal my source.
You'd dry it up, of course.
Even Niizuma won't pick
up my calls anymore.
Anyways, I've barged into Ashirogi's before, and they took care of me.
It's only proper that I go visit them.
A mangaka isn't a real
member of society.
So cruel!
I'm not a member of society anymore?
I'm already a caged bird.
No, I'm Mr. Yoshida's pet dog.
I'm not allowed to act
like a human anymore!
If I wasn't here, you'd look up his hospital and go anyways, right?
Let's just go on Monday
and get it over with, then.
In exchange, I'll be going with you, and we're coming back right away.
All right?
I heard Mashiro is in the hospital.
Yeah, I heard from Aida.
I also heard that they're on hiatus starting from issue 33.
Going on hiatus after
finally getting popular...
What bad luck.
It seems Niizuma
already went to see him.
I'm going on Monday, wanna come?
I'm pushing it every week.
I don't have that kind of time!
Come on, don't be so cold.
If I invite Miss Aoki,
she'll be sure to come.
Aoki will?
No, no.
I'm really pushing my deadline.
Would you stop tempting me like that?
I'm worried about
Mashiro, but I just can't...
Sorry.
I'll just tell him you're
concerned for him, too.
What?
She did?
Yeah, and she even propped up Saiko with her own hands.
I thought they weren't even gonna hold hands until they got married.
What's she thinking?
You'd think she would stop him.
No, this showed me once again how much she really does like him.
Huh?
I don't get it.
The ultimate love is accepting everything your partner wishes for,
and helping to achieve it.
And perhaps cooperating
with them as well.
But I would be too worried about his health and stop him.
Azuki's got a strong will.
And she really loves Saiko.
Well, it does take some strength to stay apart until their dreams come true.
They met, though.
Can they go back to staying apart now?
If they kiss in the hospital or something, I bet they won't be able to!
Kiss~
Where are you going with that?
Whatever, you don't
understand a woman's heart.
All right, the name's done.
I'll give it to Saiko even
if there's fixes to be made.
Back on track!
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
He—
He's still drawing even
though he's been hospitalized!
And his girlfriend is cute!
It's kind of tough to work in
here, and it's a bit cramped,
but I can't allow a break
in our serialization.
Look well.
Isn't he the model mangaka?
Yes...
Are you drawn to this kind
of lifestyle, Miss Girlfriend?
Um, yes.
Mr. Yoshida, when we
return, I will definitely draw.
I feel like I was mistaken...
Yes, you were.
You should feel ashamed
of yourself, Hiramaru.
Oh, if it isn't the escape artist Hiramaru.
It's been a while.
Fukuda!
Hey!
He's the author of
Kiyoshi Knight, Fukuda.
You met him earlier at
Niizuma's house, right?
Oh!
Thanks for taking care
of me then, Fukuda-sensei.
Kiyoshi 's the best!
Please give me your contact information and the address of your office, if you would—
Hey!
You're not even really
reading Jack, are you?
Seriously though,
seeing you work while hospitalized has given me a better opinion of you, Mashiro.
I won't lose to you all.
We were just talking about
him being a model mangaka.
I laughed at the "Wanted:
Hiramaru" fax from Yoshida.
Why are you laughing?
Well, I'm glad that you're lively enough to draw the manuscript.
It's pretty loud in here
for a hospital room.
Chief Editor!
I apologize, but I must ask everyone but Mashiro and Takagi to leave the room.
Why do we have to leave?
Because this has nothing to do with you.
I think it does, though.
Ashirogi Muto are my comrades.
Comrades?
You're soft.
Of course, it's written as
"comrade" but read as "rival".
Fine, you may stay.
Azuki, you stay too.
Listen, this is a hospital.
No matter what I say,
don't make a fuss.
Is it something we'd
make a fuss over?
Last night, we had a meeting regarding what to do with Shady Detective Trap.
Shady Detective Trap will be put on hiatus until next April,
when the authors
graduate from high school.
Next April?
What the hell is that?
I don't get it!
I told you not to make a fuss.
I'm kind of jealous.
W—
Why?
Why April instead of
when he's discharged?!
Right, don't be ridiculous!
Miura, you told us it was fine to start this name on Saturday!
I'm sorry...
What's the reason?
Please explain this to me!
He's right.
Let's hear it!
It's because Kawaguchi Tarou died.
The death of my uncle and our
serialization have nothing in common.
Uncle?
Died?
There was someone I knew who worked too hard on manga and died.
The person he told me
about, that was his...?
Kawaguchi Tarou was Mashiro's uncle on his father's side.
His death is firmly linked to his occupation as a mangaka.
It wouldn't be a stretch to say that he was a victim of manga.
Your mother is worried and wants you to stop drawing manga entirely.
Of course she does.
No one wants to lose their
family, the ones they love.
I won't rest.
I'll draw.
Kawaguchi Tarou never broke a serialization deadline even once.
Even when he had
a fever above 40°...
Even when he strained his
back and couldn't sit up,
he drew his manuscript while lying down.
He never went on hiatus even once.
He said he was proud of that, at least.
That is an old-fashioned way of thinking,
but it's respectable that
you don't want a hiatus.
But when the editorial department decides you need rest, then you must rest.
I don't need rest!
Let me be clear.
Continuing to draw would trouble all of us.
That's...
Get better first.
Even after he gets better,
he's still on hiatus until April.
That's right.
Aren't you contradicting yourself
by telling him to get better, then not picking the serialization back up?
The genius high schooler Niizuma Eiji.
We were impressed with his performance in serialization,
so the editorial board approved serializing authors in high school.
But a weekly serialization isn't that easy.
It was our mistake.
We regret it, and will refrain from
approving such serializations in the future.
Refrain?!
But serializations that have already started should be another matter!
You're irresponsible for
starting this policy now!
Then I'll quit school!
Me too!
There shouldn't be a problem then!
Even if you do that, I won't
lift the hiatus until April!
What Ashirogi's saying
makes more sense!
Put yourself in their parents' positions!
Dropping out of high
school to draw manga.
Will your parents be happy with that?
I don't live for my parents!
That's right! Our lives are our own!
Until April?!
A special Sunday meeting was held yesterday, and that's what was decided upon.
Why until April?
Isn't that strange?
I was interested as well,
so I asked the vice-editor,
but all he said was "It'll be a
problem if he dies on us."
Aida, do you know who
Kawaguchi Tarou was?
Of course.
Hero Legends
He was the one-hit-wonder who made Super Hero Legend.
SUPER
He didn't want to end
his career with just that,
so he continued writing names and eventually died from overwork.
That's just a rumor, right?
No, apparently, it's the truth.
What?
His real name was Mashiro Nobuhiro.
He was none other than Mashiro's uncle.
I see.
I guess they had no choice, then.
That's messed up.
Yuujirou!
He's not allowed to draw until April because he's Kawaguchi Tarou's relative?
That's unbelievable!
I think so too.
We're ignoring Mashiro's...
No, Ashirogi Muto's feelings!
If Kawaguchi Tarou wasn't my uncle...
you wouldn't be doing this.
Right?
That is correct.
That's awful.
What's with that lame excuse?
I can't listen to this!
Hiramaru!
Where are you going?
Where?
Where else would I go but back to my room to draw manga?
It's like he said.
This doesn't make sense.
Miura, this is your fault, too.
You yes-man.
Good job.
This is not Miura's fault.
On the contrary, he
resisted until the very end.
This is my decision.
I won't accept this
"hiatus until April" bull.
See you all later, Ashirogi.
I'll say it again.
Even if you draw, I won't
publish it until April.
But if you regain your health
and graduate high school,
I promise to restart
the serialization then.
Miura, I'm headed back.
I'll stay.
I see.
Dammit!
What's with this April thing?!
Takagi, Mashiro, I'm so sorry!
It's as you saw—
I have no authority.
I couldn't do anything.
Miura.
I'm the one who needs to apologize.
To Shuujin...
you...
and Azuki too.
If I hadn't gotten sick...
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault!
It's the chief editor's decision!
Yes, and it's also due
to my powerlessness.
You don't need to apologize to me.
The words I said to you the day we graduated middle school...
will hold true forever.
Take your time to get better.
What's this about graduation day?
Well, even if I ask, you
probably won't tell me.
I said I'd always be waiting.
A-Azuki...
So she is worried about his health.
"I'll always be waiting", huh.
Niizuma
Certainly!
I won't forgive the chief editor for putting Ashirogi-sensei in that situation.
Right?
Yes, it's irrational.
I won't draw for Jack until
he withdraws his decision.
Wow!
But if I'm the only one doing that, it won't make a big impact.
All right.
If they're making Trap take a break, then I'll take a break too!
But won't Ashirogi feel
guilty about that?
That's why we're going to
keep this quiet from them,
and only tell them after the editor withdraws his decision.
I see.
I'll convince Nakai and Aoki.
Oh! The entire Fukuda Team will boycott!
That's awesome!
That's not all.
Boycott!
It's wonderful!
It's fun!
Tomorrow just got a bit brighter.
April is just too long.
We've got no choice.
We're talking about
a person's life here!
Like I said, please tell us about yesterday's meeting in more detail!
Hey, Yuujirou, cut it out.
Why are you stopping me?
I just can't go along with it this time!
Right, I feel bad for Ashirogi!
The Chief Editor is back!
B-Boycott?
We won't draw Kiyoshi, Crow, or Otters 11
until he withdraws his decision.
No objection.
And if he doesn't give in,
I'll draw for another magazine until Ashirogi can draw again.
You're going that far?
But you have a contract,
so you can't do that...
I'll return the down
payment and do it!
If it comes down to it, I'll pay the termination fees for Ashirogi-sensei
and everyone else so we can migrate to another magazine!
I want to keep drawing
manga, you know.
But, well...
Nakai, you're not manly
enough at times like these.
I feel that the Chief
Editor is going too far.
We should fight against it.
Oh, Miss Aoki, this is the first time we've agreed on something.
For a boycott, the more
people we have, the better.
You're on fire today!
I also like you.
H-Hey, Hiramaru!
What are you trying to
pull in this confusion?
Forgive me.
You see, I'm weak
against beautiful women.
Fine, I'll do it.
I'm worried about them, too.
I'm in.
I'm back.
Oh, welcome back.
Hey.
It's too quiet in here.
We heard about Ashirogi.
Yeah.
It's awful.
We can't just keep quiet about this.
Let's protest it.
Hey, the Chief Editor is just outside.
Keep it down.
And even if you protest, there's no way he'd change his mind once it's made up.
Fukuda?
Boycott?
What do you mean by that?
"If arrangements are not made for Trap's early return, we will also go on hiatus."
"We..."?
Kiyoshi Knight, Crow, Otters 11...
Otters as well?
And also, Hideout Door.
Hi-door too?
They each took the
phone and announced it.
That's five series counting Trap.
It'll be a huge problem
if they all go on hiatus!
Hey, where are you going?
Since they've gone out of their way to tell us, I'll let the Chief Editor know.
Don't, idiot!
It's the editors' job to
make the authors draw!
We can't just accept it quietly!
Yuujirou, everyone was on
the same phone, right?
Yeah.
Which means they're all in
the same place right now.
I'll go.
Try asking them where they are.
I'll go, too.
I'm in charge of Fukuda and Niizuma.
This is a problem regarding
Trap, so I'll come too.
I'm coming too.
Listen, when we leave the department,
let's go in ones and twos
so we don't raise suspicion.
Yeah.
At the nearest family restaurant.
There are five of us here.
All of our editors, plus Hattori, are coming in secret without the Chief Editor knowing.
They're taking us on!
It's a battle between
authors and editors!
Oh! EXCITING!
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiruno?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yumemireruno?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
tooriame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo motte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari desaemo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsuhidasu nandodemo
I can picture them... countless times
nandodemo
over and over again
Next
Episode
We're boycotting until the decision about Ashirogi's hiatus is reversed!
It seems like an
unprecedented situation will occur.
It's unprecedented that you
and I agree on something!
Next time on Bakuman:
Recall and
Call
Recall and Call.
I won't forgive a guy
who crushes dreams!