January 17th, Day of the New Year's Party
And now I'd like to ask Akimoto-sensei to lead the toast on behalf of all the authors.
Isn't it frustrating that Kiyoshi Knight didn't win?
But I should accept the result gracefully.
I thought your one-shot for the Tezuka Award was superb.
Aoki Kou.
What's your real name?
Aoki Yuriko.
Yuri, huh.
Do you like my music?
I like most of your lyrics, but not the melodies.
It's good to be straightforward.
But do you like me as a mangaka?
Yes.
Your sad face is lovely too.
I want to turn it into a song.
I'd rather you turn it into a manga than a song.
That chief editor is pretty good, setting all this up.
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Window and Snow
February 22
I'm answering it.
Okay.
This is Takagi.
Congrats!
It got third place in initial polls!
Third?
With a rank like that,
you can just go with the first storyline you made for chapter four.
Um, should we really be
satisfied with third place?
Shouldn't a first chapter
usually get first place?
Come on, you got third in Jack, the top shounen magazine!
Be happy!
But Hiramaru's Otter 11, which started two volumes before us,
got first place with its first chapter.
First Place
Yeah, Otter had a great start.
His second chapter got third place, and his third chapter got fourth place.
It's amazing.
Arai-sensei's Baked Cheese started last week,
and the first chapter got third place, right?
How'd his second chapter do?
Ninth.
Ninth?
So then, we can expect Trap's ranking to fall that much for the second chapter?
What do you mean?
If the second chapter stays in the top ten, that's an accomplishment!
Besides, Trap's second and
third chapters are well done.
Don't be such a downer!
Have some confidence in your work!
He'll tell us the rest at
Friday's meeting, he says.
All right.
Huh?
This was a good result, right?
Right? Right?
Yeah.
But we lost the best chance
to claim the top spot.
Saiko, I thought you'd be disappointed getting third but you seem fine with it.
I am disappointed!
I want to get higher results.
I wanted to get first place.
But I'm more relieved that the ranking isn't worse than it is.
Besides, we're aiming for the top spot with a long-running serialization, right?
Yeah, you're right.
And next up is the decisive second chapter!
Place
Otters Eleven
Baked Cheese
I hope we don't fall as much as Cheese did.
Miura is a bit too optimistic.
Let's brace ourselves for now.
We can't expect to get any higher.
We're still young.
Come on, we're still in high school!
Anyway, the deadline for chapter four is Friday.
I have to pen-in as much as I can and get it ready for the assistants.
Saiko, you're calm about this.
There's no point in rushing.
I got it!
Miho said it was good in an email, right?
Oh, I see how it is.
Can you guys get going?
You don't have any work to do here, right?
You're right, sorry for barging in.
'Kay.
Good luck, Mashiro!
See ya later.
Okay.
Is this the first email she's sent me since the photo book thing?
Azuki Miho
Congrats
I saw the first chapter of Trap.
It was really good. I'm looking forward
to the second chapter
I saw the first chapter of Trap. www.
It was really good. I'm looking.
to the second chapte
The second chapter, huh?
The real fight is coming up next!
But I think I'll reply first!
Shady Detective Trap got a pretty good start, huh?
Yes, I'm relieved.
Nice...
Very nice.
I'm so glad I asked you.
As I thought, your style suits us much better.
More than Shounen.
Thank you.
Why is Aoki meeting with
the head editor of Jack SQ?
She's doing an original work with Koogy.
What?!
Is that okay, Aida?
Aren't you her editor?
A while ago, I asked her to
polish up Hideout Door
in preparation for the next
serialization meeting, but...
Battling?
Yeah. The editorial department thinks the characters need to fight against something, shounen-style.
There are already psychological
struggles in the story.
Well, that's not exactly what we want.
You want punching and kicking, then?
Yes, to put it simply.
If we leave the drawing to Nakai, it'll work out somehow.
I don't want to change the content of the plot.
Because I don't think my story is bad.
She's not willing to be flexible.
So, Chief Editor Ibaraki of Jack SQ invited her to come over to his magazine.
Niizuma
Wha?!
Are you for real, Yuujirou?
Then I'll tell him.
'Kay?
Got it.
Later.
Nakai.
Miss Aoki's gonna start a serialization together with Koogy.
Huh?
The chief editor of Jack SQ secretly introduced them at the New Year's party.
So then, Aoki is...
If the deal has gone that far, she's probably not against it—
Sorry, I'm going out for a bit.
I want to tell my story to
the readers no matter what.
I want them to understand it.
My story isn't the problem.
Yes?
Aoki, it's me, Nakai.
I'll just speak from out here, so please listen to what I have to say.
What's this all of a sudden?
Is it true you're pairing up
with Koogy... no, Makaino?
It is.
Then, what about me?
We're over.
Why?
Hideout Door is a wonderful work!
If you submit it to the next serialization committee, it'll definitely pass!
So why are you doing this?
Your art can't convey
my worldview or my story.
My art...
All right, then.
I'll draw so that it definitely satisfies you!
I'll work hard on it!
I'll depict the world of Aoki Kou!
You're Niizuma's assistant, so you can't take the time to do that.
I'll practice without sleep!
You can say that as many times as you like.
There's a park behind this
apartment complex, right?
When I'm done with work, I'll sit there and draw every day!
You'll be able to see me from your window!
I'll use every free moment to draw!
Watch me!
Please stop it.
You're disturbing me.
I won't stop!
Until I can draw art that
satisfies you, I'll never stop!
Nakai's an idiot.
It's pointless trying to convince a girl that drops you when she gets a taste of fame.
That's how much he risked
on Hideout Door, right?
Nakai, didn't you leave for the day?
No, just came back to get
my supplies and the storyline.
Did you talk to Miss Aoki?
Hmm, I'll want a flashlight.
What're you doing?
I'm going to draw at Aoki's place.
Until she's satisfied.
What?
Her place... you mean in her apartment?!
Not in her apartment.
Outside of it!
Outside?!
In this cold weather?
Yeah. See you tomorrow.
What the heck is he thinking?
About manga, surely.
All right.
I've got the fourth chapter now.
Yes.
Your first chapter got third
place in the final results too.
You're off to a good start.
Yeah...
You guys are third in Jack ! Cheer up!
Ah, well...
We're just hoping we don't drop with the second chapter.
You guys are real downers.
Just be happy you're in third place.
Let's aim for long-term serialization!
Yes.
Oh, speaking of serialization...
Koogy's started serializing with Jack SQ, I hear.
Really.
Koogy?
Even more, he's partnering with Aoki.
Today, he called for a press conference...
When it's announced, there'll be a big fuss.
Starting with Jack SQ,
I'll take the top of the manga world!
Aoki and Koogy?
Well, that's a different publication, so it's really got nothing to do with us!
Does Nakai know already?
I wonder.
Saiko, let's try calling him.
But what should we say?
Then, let's try probing Fukuda for info first.
Okay...
I'll be leaving for today.
Spin!! Good work today.
It's from Mashiro.
Tell him that their first chapter was good.
Yo.
Trap's serialization started!
Niizuma said to tell you it was good.
Thank you.
Um, there's something we're a bit concerned about.
What?
It's about Nakai.
We heard that Aoki was
partnering up with Koogy...
It's not something you
guys should worry about.
Did something happen?
Don't worry about that,
just focus on your serialization.
Got it?
Now that he told us not to worry, I'm even more worried!
Me too.
I also think Nakai really likes Aoki.
I don't think Nakai can
deal with a shock like that!
I'm so worried about it,
I can't concentrate on writing!
But I think what Fukuda said is right.
Being serialized is tougher than I thought.
Right now, we just have to
move forward as best we can.
But if you're worried, why not just call him?
If you can't concentrate on your work...
Yeah, that's true.
Let's just ask him.
Fukuda, it's Mashiro.
Yeah.
Well, um, is Nakai okay?
We're really worried about him.
Oh fine, whatever.
I'll tell you what's going on.
For the past four days, every moment he hasn't been working,
Nakai's been drawing in the park in front of Miss Aoki's place.
Okay...
I don't really get it...
He's drawing the manuscript at night where she can see him from her window.
Get it?
Outside?!
It's February!
It's useless! His hands will be frozen!
Why is he doing that?
To get Miss Aoki back, of course!
He just seems like a
stalker to me, though.
I'm betting my future as a mangaka on this work of Aoki's!
If it doesn't work, I'll be an assistant for life, or I'll go back home to my folks!
Um, is he still drawing now?
Yeah.
It's already past midnight!
Hello?
Please stop this.
I'll be inconvenienced
if you freeze to death.
I-It's not cold!
My mind and body are on fire!
More importantly, you've been watching me.
Thank you.
I want to work with you once again.
I'll definitely draw art
that you can approve of!
I want to draw your world!
Hello?
Fukuda?
Mashiro.
Yes?
I was going to drag him back,
but after seeing him, I don't
have the heart to stop him.
Even if he dies like this, he'll be happy.
"Even if he dies"...
Dies!?
For real?
That's not it...
Fukuda, I get even more worried when you use words like that.
That's why I told you to quit worrying and focus on your serialization!
Don't call me again!
I wonder if Nakai is going
to back to Aoki's place today.
Probably.
He's entrenched himself there.
I guess I shouldn't have asked.
I just worry about him all the time.
But I have to finish up the manuscript.
Really, she's so mean!
If this Aoki person really didn't want him there, she'd call the police and they'd make him leave.
Oh yeah, she could do that.
In that case, should I contact the police?
If you do that, Nakai
would curse you for life.
Huh?
Then, this woman doesn't call the police because she doesn't want him to hate her?
I dunno...
maybe she's just testing him.
Maybe...
in her heart, she still has doubts.
Don't touch it with your filthy hands!
Old man, did you just call me filthy?
I don't want you to touch my manuscript.
You're way more filthy!
Just spare my hand!
Jeez, this guy creeps me out.
Let's leave him and go have fun.
Yeah.
Come on, let's go!
Today, again...
I could just peek inside.
Amazing!
In that cold park, he drew
something so perfectly...
Our second chapter's in publication.
Yeah.
What do you think the polls will say?
We've done all that we can.
All that's left is to wait for the results.
Right now, it's more important to pen-in the fifth chapter.
It's crazy out there!
It's snowing really hard.
It's already starting to pile up.
I'm so cold!
That's right, the weather report said there'd be a snowstorm.
Snowstorm?!
What, Mashiro?
Hungry
Pork
Stew
Hungry
Pork
Stew
Fukuda, where are you now?
At Niizuma's office.
I'm writing my own manga's plot here.
Hungry
Pork
Stew
Hungry
Pork
Stew
It's got heat.
Where's Nakai?
In the park, as usual.
It's snowing pretty heavily here.
How is it there?
Snow?
Wow! It's really coming down here!
If he's drawing manga in
this snow, he'll die for real!
But even if I had backup,
I probably couldn't budge him.
Nakai wants to prove he's a man.
I said it before, but this is
an ambition he'll die for.
It's his decisi—
Fukuda! What are you saying?!
Nakai is a member of your Fukuda team!
I cant take this anymore.
I'll make him go home, by force if I have to!
Okay, I'll go.
We'll come too.
Where should we go?
It's in Mitaka.
When you get to the train station, call me.
Nakai.
Fukuda.
Let's go home.
If you draw in this weather, you'll die.
No, I won't go home.
What are you talking about?
Freezing to death for that cold-hearted woman doesn't even make for a good joke!
I'm betting everything on Hideout Door.
I know that Aoki isn't bending
or changing her opinion.
It may seem cold to other people.
But I think with what I draw, I can turn it around into something with passion.
Fukuda, we're at the station.
In front of the ticket gate.
All right, I'll come get you.
Ashirogi ran here because
they're worried about you.
I'm grateful, but it's pointless.
I have no intention of stopping.
I want to work with you once again!
I'll draw so that it definitely satisfies you!
I'll depict your world!
Dammit.
The snow's getting thicker!
At this rate, he'll really be in trouble!
But why is he going to such lengths?
I don't get it either!
I don't think it's just because he likes Aoki!
Yeah.
It's more than just liking her, he's also in love with her work!
Right!
And his passion for manga
is what's motivating him.
But even if he's got passion,
if he hurts himself...
I know!
Nakai's my buddy in the Fukuda team!
I'll definitely take him home!
Fukuda?
I already told you I won't go home.
I'm sorry.
Over here!
In this park—
I'm sorry.
It's not your art that was bad.
It was me.
And I didn't want to admit it.
I was running from it.
I'll write a story that'll
be worthy of your art.
Aoki, that's not true.
My art wasn't strong enough.
I'm so glad!
Is that it?
Guess there wasn't
any point in you coming.
I suppose so.
Please come in and warm yourself up.
Eh? C-Can I really, really come in-into...
That was just too creepy!
I take it back!
I only invited you in just as a working partner...
It feels like our rival came back with a power-up.
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Yeah.
So sorry!
I'm so sorry! So sorry!
I see.
All right.
Tell Aoki to do her best.
Later.
So Aoki Kou couldn't become the person who understood me.
To be a genius really is to be lonely.
It doesn't matter.
So in the end, Koogy will draw by himself.
They said it on TV.
And after that, Nakai got a
fever and couldn't move.
Fukuda complained that he had trouble getting him home.
But now we can concentrate on Trap.
#5 manuscript UP
Yeah.
It's here!
This is Takagi!
How are the results for the second chapter?
Eighth?
Our decisive second chapter...
got eighth?
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiruno
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yumemireruno?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
tooriame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo motte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari desaemo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsuhidasu nandodemo
I can picture them... countless times
nandodemo
over and over again
Our decisive second chapter got eighth place.
Next
Episode
What will our next rank be?
We should support each other and move on.
Let's take it slow! No hurry, no hurry.
You support yourself!
Support and
Patience
Next time on Bakuman:
Support and Patience.
We've begun to turn our dreams to reality!