Huh?
It feels like it's lost some of its 'oomph' compared to when it was in Next.
It looks much better
than the Next one-shot!
It's pretty good,
but it's going to take some work to keep it from getting boring if it gets serialized.
I'm excited to see what happens next. It's perfect for a serialization.
It's...
I'm looking forward to tomorrow's serialization committee!
It'll be okay...
right?
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream.
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Special Relationship and Hometown
Ca— May I come in please?!
My name is Takagi Akito.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Oh, ahem.
I'm Kaya's father.
We've been dating
since middle school,
and now we're in the same college.
W-Well, have a seat.
Th-Thank you.
Can we stop this?
This is pretty embarrassing.
We can practice the greeting
after we get serialized!
Besides, I don't even
know what your dad's like!
Geez, you're too shy.
Ad-libbing isn't working!
H-He's the CEO of a
company, isn't he?
Yeah, but it's only a small real estate company in Yakusa.
So you're the only
daughter of a CEO?
Yeah.
He also teaches karate
in a nearby dojo.
You'd better prepare yourself.
Don't scare me like that.
We've got both a serialization
and a marriage riding
on what happens today.
I'm already at a crossroads in life.
Ta-da! A marriage registration form!
You already got one?!
You jumped the gun!
What's wrong?
This is how you get registered!
We can only do that
after we get serialized
and get permission from our parents!
It's fine to get the form in advance!
Takahama
It's all about a man's technique!
Well, I mean his manga technique.
Oh you, Nakai.
Katou, what do you think
of a guy who has technique?
I'm talking about manga, of course.
What?
What's with that question?
Um, I haven't mentioned this,
but Business Boy Kenichi
might be canceled in
today's serialization meeting.
I didn't know.
If it does end,
we'll have to part ways
with each other again.
Part ways?
But even if it ends,
we can still see
each other, right?
Yeah, since we've
gotten to know each other,
we could talk on the
phone sometimes.
Only on the phone?
Well, meeting up would
be kind of weird...
we're not dating, or anything.
Natsumi, is that all you felt for me?
R-Right...
There's no way you would
have feelings for me...
Me and you?
Please don't joke about that.
Besides, I prefer younger men.
I was pretty serious about you though...
Oh, there you go again...
You really shouldn't.
Please don't have
this conversation here!
Right! I'm sorry!
This is the first time I've
seen Takahama get angry.
Since he's this irritated,
it must mean Business Boy
Kenichi is in deep trouble.
My stomach hurts!
Miura, don't be so uptight.
Only eight names were submitted,
so even if only two pass, that means you already have a 25% chance.
And judging by Tanto's quality,
I'd say it's a 50% chance.
Arai's is definitely in, so
if two new ones start up,
you'll only have a 1 in 7
chance of being the other one.
Yamahisa, that's enough out of you.
Scary.
And I told Ashirogi
that they only needed three solid chapters to pass for sure...
If they don't get serialized, then...
Congratulations!
Time of Blue Leaves will start
its serialization in the
second issue of the new year!
Really?
Thank you!
Everyone thinks it's much
better than the Next one-shot.
It's like a surprise comeback!
It's all thanks to
Fukuda and everyone...
I have to thank them properly.
Unlike in your previous series where you only did the manuscript,
this time you'll need a
few assistants to help you.
Can they work at your home?
Yes, I'll manage.
But I'd like all female
assistants, if possible.
I understand.
I'll arrange it as
quickly as possible.
What?
Only four more chapters?
The new serializations are...
Time of Blue Leaves, and...
Miura, I don't need to
know what's starting.
Time of Blue Leaves...
that's Aoki...
You two can leave for today.
I want to be alone for a while.
Okay.
Have a good evening.
Dammit!
What?!
It didn't pass?
Hey, don't get so down.
We just have to make it even better and submit it to the next committee.
It'll definitely pass next time...
But you said it would pass as long as we had three chapters.
They just have really high
expectations for you guys.
This was a good thing.
You could even say
it was for the best...
Ah, sorry, but Business
Boy Kenichi is ending,
so I have to go meet with Takahama.
Business Boy Kenichi was canceled?
Maybe he was too young...
Is that how it is?
I knew getting a serialization
wasn't going to be that easy.
Why didn't it pass?
Isn't it strange?
Takagi, you didn't want to get married, so you let the quality slip!
I'd never do that!
Who's starting?
Arai and Aoki.
She is?
She got ahead of us.
Miura's too optimistic.
It concerns me that
Takahama's also ended.
We've got the same editor.
But it was thanks to Miura
that we got 1st place in Next!
We've got no choice
but to trust him!
Right, we'll definitely
get serialized next time.
Let's have faith in that
and keep our heads up!
Yeah!
My marriage got pushed off.
S-Sorry.
It's ending.
Only four more chapters.
Katou!
Before it ends, there's
something I want to clarify...
I'm sorry!
I can't have a special
relationship with you.
No way...
Is this the end?
I know!
Aoki's got a new serialization.
She should need assistants now...
After that happened, I can't...
No, it'll only be for work.
If I say I'll just be an assistant...
This is Nakai.
I heard you got serialized,
and I thought you might
be needing assistants.
Not drawing the art, just assisting...
I think there's something else you should say to me before that.
But even if you apologized,
I've decided that all of my
assistants will be female,
so there wouldn't be much of a point.
Y-You won't reconsider?
The serialization I was
assisting with is ending,
and Natsumi and I will
part ways when it's over...
Goodbye.
Please do not call me again.
You rejected Nakai?
I told him I wouldn't have a special relationship with him.
Is that why...
Nakai's going back to the country?!
Yeah, I just called him,
Takahama Shouyou
and he said he's quitting
manga and going back home!
Because he was rejected by Katou?
And Aoki before that.
Even though he's
that kind of person,
there aren't many people
with art as good as his.
We should try to stop him...
Takahama Shouyou
Th-Thanks for telling us.
So it's Mashiro this time?
Why are you going back home?
Your art's amazing!
It's such a waste!
That art led me down the wrong path.
I abused it.
I'm disgusted with myself.
B-But...
There's no use trying to stop me.
Tomorrow, I'm clearing out
everything and leaving.
Bye.
Nakai!
He hung up on me.
What should we do?
I don't feel like stopping him.
He's done some bad stuff.
It serves him right.
Shuujin.
That's cold.
I'm going home to think
of some gags. See ya.
I'll definitely get serialized!
We can't do anything unless Nakai works up some resolve himself.
Anything we try would just
be butting into his business,
and wouldn't accomplish anything.
I can't stop him.
I told him never to
call me again yesterday.
It's like Shuujin said.
It serves him right, huh?
Nakai.
Mashiro.
My hometown's a place called Akita.
They grow apples and rice.
I'll send you a bunch of apples.
Please don't leave.
You're the one who taught me the basics of backgrounds!
I see.
Then I'm glad I drew
manga, if only for that.
Like you, all I can do is draw!
You were my inspiration!
Don't...
don't give up on your dream!
Thanks.
But like I said yesterday,
I don't have the right to
draw manga anymore.
Take care of yourself.
Raindrop Apartments
Fukuda! Aoki!
Thank you for your help
with Hideout Door.
I'm sorry for all the
trouble I caused you.
You won't let it end
like this, will you?!
How is it?
It's well done.
It does better than I thought
as a shounen manga.
It's all thanks to your coaching.
I just did as you told me.
Can you write the rest?
Even though you said it was only going to be a 45 page one-shot?
Yes.
I want to read the rest now.
Stick to the basics
that I've taught you,
but this time, I want
you to write freely.
Will something I come up with on my own be acceptable?
Of course, I'll look at it and point out the parts that need fixing.
If it's bad, I'll tell you why.
At any rate,
I want to see how far
you can get on your own.
I understand.
She did everything I told her.
With this, she can...
What can we fix in this name?
That's what we're gonna discuss in the meeting today, right?
There's a limit to how
many gags we can put in.
If it needs any changing, wouldn't it be better to change the whole plot?
Well, I think so too...
If only eight names
were submitted this time,
there will be a lot more next time.
And only two or three get serialized.
At least now I know that Miura's "Definitely!" isn't a sure thing.
Will we really make it
with him as our editor?
What are you mumbling about?
We won't make it on time
if we don't leave now!
Yeah.
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
Aida, what do you think the best way to rework this name would be?
I can't think of any way to improve it.
Then just submit it to
the next committee as-is.
You're cold.
Just tell them what the
committee's opinions were.
You're right.
Since Business Boy Kenichi ended, I'm not editing any serialized manga.
I have to get serialized
at the next committee...
Yuujirou.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Basically, the part you
did in the one-shot
lost its impact in the serialization name.
This will always happen,
especially with gag manga.
We have to power it up!
We just need to think
about how to do it!
Even if you say "power it up",
we've exhausted the
possibilities with the characters.
A rival!
There's no rival yet!
You said that if it ever
became a battle manga,
you'd write in an evil inventor.
Oh!
That's a rival, isn't it?
Lets go with that!
Leave the first chapter as is...
and introduce the evil
inventor in the second!
Oh, sorry.
This is Miura.
Takahama's come to see me.
Huh?
I believe you should
also be present.
Come to the editing department.
I'm currently in a meeting with Ashirogi on the first floor,
but should I come up right now?
Bring Ashirogi too.
Takahama?
Why did he go straight to the Chief Editor and not Miura?
Takahama has asked
me to change his editor.
Why?!
Because he won't let
me draw what I want.
Is that all?
Yes.
Listen.
"He won't let me draw what I want"...
is an admission that you
don't have any talent.
If what you wanted to draw produced an excellent shounen manga,
then it would be accepted as-is.
Because it is not, it means that you do not have the ability to do so.
"He won't let me draw what I want"...
It does seems like an excuse.
I believe that an author who blames
the editing department or his editor for a work that doesn't produce results
is most foolish.
If you disagree with your editor
and believe you are
right no matter what,
then draw a shounen manga that will force him to agree.
There are works that
have succeeded that way.
In a way, those works
are the real thing.
Yes, sir.
I won't change your editor.
It's not because you're a newcomer.
I won't make exceptions,
even for great and
influential authors.
If you truly cannot
get along with Miura,
then you can draw
for another magazine.
I will take care of
ending the contract.
I-I understand.
Sorry for being so conceited.
Takahama, if you have issues with me, please tell me directly.
I'll fix what I'm doing wrong.
Let's work together.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
The Chief Editor sure was scary today.
I really empathized with Takahama.
We've badmouthed Miura too.
Let's stop putting all
the blame on our editor.
Yeah.
I'm regretting it now.
This is good.
I think I've heard the name Akina Aiko somewhere before...
Who is it?
She's this year's Pleiades
amateur contest winner.
So why is she writing
a manga manuscript?
Keep this a secret, okay?
She's Takagi's rival.
His rival?
Well, she may be a rival in
terms of manuscript writing,
but who's doing the art?
Nakai?
No...
Someone who can draw it at a level that can compete with Ashirogi Muto.
Compete with Ashirogi?
Who?
Mashiro's art is really something.
Niizuma Eiji!
Niizuma?!
But...
Well...
Niizuma
Eiji  Ltd.
And then? And then?
It was born!
It's not a chick!
Huh?
This is a great manuscript!
Are they going to fight after this?
Or...
Next! Give me the next chapter!
There isn't one yet.
There isn't?
There isn't one?
It ended at a good place too.
Are you making this into a one-shot?
Who's drawing it?
It hasn't been decided yet.
I'm looking for any artist
who can draw it well.
Can I draw it, then?
Hey!
Just wait a minute!
You can't take a break from Crow.
Neglect it in any way,
and the deal's off!
I don't care about the
character designs right now.
Can you make a name for me?
Roger!
Hey, were you listening to me?
Spin, spin...
A circle here, a circle there...
Drawing an interesting story I could have never come up with is fun too!
And right here, hot hot hot...
Here it is!
Scary, so scary.
It's finished.
Crap, it's too good.
I thought it would
make the story better,
but not by this much!
We have to do this.
Wait, but what'll happen
if this is accepted?
Niizuma, I'm going to have the higher ups take a look at this.
But only on the condition
that you keep doing Crow
and keep the quality up.
It passes?
Can I draw it?
But if I'm going to draw it...
I'll only do it as a serialization.
Don't be ridiculous!
All right.
I'm already having her
write a second chapter.
I'll have her write a third
and submit it to the next
serialization committee.
Hattori!
Akina's been Takagi's rival
since middle school.
If we do this, it'll definitely
fire up Ashirogi Muto!
Yuujirou, I definitely want
this to get serialized.
But two works by the same author
getting serialized at the same time?!
It's fine, it just hasn't
happened before.
He'll have an impossible schedule!
But you know I can make a name in a day, and a manuscript in two!
Damn, he can do it if
we get more assistants.
And she'll be the one writing
the manuscripts, anyway.
It'll be a piece of cake!
How are we going to explain
this to the higher-ups?
Niizuma, can you draw this
as if you were someone else?
It's fine as long as they
don't know I'm drawing it?
"A new, outstanding artist
has appeared."
Roger!
We'll pass it out with
him using a pen name,
and if it passes at the
committee, reveal the truth.
If it passes and we
reveal that it was Niizuma,
they'll have no
choice but to do it.
Secret plans are fun!
Hattori, was this your
aim from the beginning?
What?
From the chicken comes an egg, from the egg comes a chicken!
No, I'd never thought it'd get this far.
It's getting Niizuma fired up again, and it won't interfere with Crow.
If we have authors with a strong sense of rivalry compete with each other,
it can only be a good thing for Jack.
This is a good chance.
If this works, I'll get
promoted to lead editor!
I might even be put on the
serialization committee...
Hattori, if this goes well,
let's split the credit.
Right.
Until this passes at the committee, it'll be a secret project.
I'll be the first mangaka
with two serializations in Jack!
SPIN!
toomawari wo eranda no wa
The reason I chose to take a detour
motto kimi wo suki ni naru tame datta n da
was to fall ever deeper in love with you
boku no namae yobu sono koe wo
I have a feeling I've always known
zutto zutto shitteta ki ga shita n da
what your voice sounds like when it calls my name
boku no yubisaki de egaita
With my fingertips I drew
subete no sen wa kimi ni tsuzuku kakehashi sa
many lines that make up a suspension bridge leading to you
Show me the way bokura no michi kitto
Show me the way I'm sure our path
Believe in your way hitosuji ni tsunagari
Believe in your way connects us without any turns
Show me the way yakusoku no basho e tsuzuku
Show me the way It leads to the place where we promised
Show me the way akirametari shinaide
Show me the way I will never give up
Believe in your way sono hitomi wo agete
Believe in your way Raise your gaze
Show me the way bokura wa massugu deau sa
Show me the way and see that we're certain to meet again
Next
Episode
Now, here comes my counterattack!
Sounds like a pretty
scary development.
You'll regret this! I'll
bring you to your knees!
Next time on Bakuman:
Complaint
and Roar
Complaint and Roar.
It might be a driving
force for any dream!