toomawari wo eranda no wa
The reason I chose to take a detour
motto kimi wo suki ni naru tame datta n da
was to fall ever deeper in love with you
boku no namae yobu sono koe wo
I have a feeling I've always known
zutto zutto shitteta ki ga shita n da
what your voice sounds like when it calls my name
boku no yubisaki de egaita
With my fingertips I drew
subete no sen wa kimi ni tsuzuku kakehashi sa
many lines that make up a suspension bridge leading to you
(Show me the way) bokura no michi kitto
(Show me the way) I'm sure our path
(Believe in your way) hitosuji ni tsunagari
(Believe in your way) connects us without any turns
(Show me the way) yakusoku no basho e tsuzuku
(Show me the way) It leads to the place where we promised
(Show me the way) akirametari shinaide
(Show me the way) I will never give up
(Believe in your way) sono hitomi wo agete
(Believe in your way) Raise your gaze
(Show me the way) bokura wa massugu deau sa
(Show me the way) and see that we're certain to meet again