Komane...
zumi!
Well, it's a ripoff, so it's not really good.
Don't do it, then.
Then, the next gag.
Kaya, hit me here.
Salmon Pink!
You prepared that?
Boring.
Right, okay.
Next.
This is one I thought of
based on Tanto's hairdo.
It's not a wig!
How's this?
Well, it's...
I dunno about that...
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Love and Denial
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
V Jack
Akina Aiko confessed to you?!
Well, during our
meeting yesterday...
What's wrong?
You haven't fixed the
areas I've pointed out.
This isn't like you.
I'm sorry.
Do let me know if
something is bothering you.
If it's something I
can help with, I will.
Am I appealing as a woman?
Er, what exactly do you mean by that?
Do you see me as
an attractive woman?
...is what she said.
And how'd you respond?
I said something like,
"Men your age would
surely find you attractive."
You're an idiot!
You should take advantage of that to make her write better!
No way!
I can't use a 19 year old
girl's feelings like that.
As I person, I can't...
But you, of all guys?
I could understand if
it was Niizuma, though.
Those two don't suit
each other at all!
Speaking of Niizuma,
he said he's not reading Tanto.
I dunno about that.
That's your catchphrase?
Uh, yes.
It actually becomes a habit.
It means something when you catch yourself doing it, right?
But, it's...
Ah, I dunno about that.
L-Look!
I-Indeed...
Okay, let's try putting it
in several times per week.
Okay!
The seventh chapter got 12th place.
Thinking up the gags took a lot of time this week,
Even though it's stable,
so I didn't have time for the name...
it's definitely not a good rank.
What?! That's not good.
Well, you can turn it in
by Monday at the latest.
But you've always had it by Friday.
I'm sorry.
I'll definitely have it by tomorrow.
Oh, right.
Hattori told me to tell you something.
Natural is already being
fought over by the TV stations.
An anime adaptation?
Anime, drama,
and even offers for a
live-action film, it seems.
Wow.
There's not even 10 chapters yet!
And...
It seems like Niizuma's
not reading Tanto anymore.
Eiji, a self-proclaimed fan
of Ashirogi isn't reading it...
Does that mean the fans
think that Tanto is no good?
Mashiro-sensei!
Does this mean we'll be
finishing on Monday from now on?
Um, I think that's how
it's going to go for a bit.
Do you still need weekends off after all?
No, I'm good.
Orihara.
When a manuscript comes in,
look over the whole thing first.
Oh, right!
Not even a wry smile from either of them...
Akito.
Are you not sleeping tonight, either?
Yeah.
I dunno about two
all nighters in a row...
I dunno about that...
Our ranking isn't going up.
Ever since we added
"I dunno" in the 10th chapter,
we've been at 12th place or worse.
W-Well, you just put it in.
Something like this will only show results if you're persistent!
Right.
Thanks for your work.
Saiko, how long can
you wait for the name?
I have some breathing
room from the double issue,
but I'd say no more than a week.
Thought so.
Then it might be two to
three days later than usual.
Fine,
but wouldn't you have
to put off the vacation
you planned after your
wedding ceremony in June?
If you don't leave
yourself enough time...
I know.
My livelihood is depending on it,
so I have to work hard.
Sorry, but I'm leaving early.
Yes, Miyoshi—
I mean, Miss Takagi Kaya?
Akito just called and said
he was coming home now...
He's been working through
the night for three days straight now.
You were hospitalized before,
so I'm worried about him.
I get it.
I'll tell him not to
push himself too hard.
Shuujin's doing his best.
But...
Because...
Yeah,
she's not a very cute
elementary schooler
But I guess taking them overseas
from a young age is spoiling them.
Meanwhile...
_
Metaru
Laboratory
Ah,
you're
going too
What!!
If you wait, we'll
definitely take
you to Hawaii
They'll take me
to Hawaii!
It seems that Niizuma
doesn't read Tanto anymore.
Dammit!
I can't think of anything!
Is he planning on going without sleep until our wedding in two days?
Crap!
Azuki Miho
Miho?
Sorry, are you still awake?
Yeah.
Only two days left!
I wanted to talk to you one more time before your honeymoon.
It's hardly a honeymoon!
Only three days and two
nights at a hot spring.
In elementary school,
you said you'd never get married!
Wedding Ceremony
Oh, did I say that?
You did!
Right.
Miho, back then...
Akito, Kaya, congratulations
on your marriage!
I clearly and fondly remember
when Akito and Mashiro Moritaka
came to me for a consultation.
It's been 5 years since then, and they have
produced one wonderful work after another...
I'm so jealous!
So why isn't Akina here?
Hiramaru, you're being annoying.
...they handed me The Two Earths.
Next, they aimed for the Tezuka Prize with One in a Hundred Million.
Then they debuted in Next
with Money and Intelligence,
and finally got their first serialization in Jack, Shady Detective Trap.
From reading these works,
I know these two have talent.
One day,
they will become famous mangakas who will support Shounen Jack.
I believe in this.
He didn't say anything about Tanto.
Akito is a lucky man to have a wife like
Kaya and a partner like Moritaka Mashiro.
Eiji,
and now Hattori...
I can only think they're
disappointed in us.
Um... ah...
Akito, Kaya...
th-thank yo—er, I mean, congratulations!
Hattori.
What is it?
Tell me up front.
Tell you what?
Is it of your opinion
that Tanto doesn't suit us,
and that we should quit?
You're serialized.
You can't quit.
If you do, it'll cause a scene.
You know what it means
to be a new author with two series that have been canceled quickly, right?
It won't go over well
with Miura, either.
I don't even think
Takagi will take it well.
Furthermore, Ashirogi has already been labeled as a troublemaker.
If you do something that selfish,
your contract may even be cut—
Tell me clearly!
Tell me to quit!
Saiko!
What?
Mashiro?
Mashiro, this is a celebration.
If you insist on having this conversation, let's take it outside.
Yes, let's.
Saiko and Hattori...
What's going on?
From his grim expression,
something must be up.
The groom mustn't leave his seat.
Well, but...
I know.
You're not our editor,
so you won't give us
your opinion directly.
Are the rules of the editing
department that strict?
If you have something to
say, just tell me directly!
Are you going to do
whatever I tell you?
You and Takagi just have to follow the path you chose and believed in!
That's what you've
always done, right?
How far are you going to go to avoid saying what you think about Tanto?
You could at least
give me some advice!
Just tell me whether you
think it's good or not—
It's not!
Personally,
I don't think it's good.
Ever since I saw your
manuscript five years ago,
I've believed that you
can surpass Niizuma Eiji!
Let's get back to the wedding.
Thank you... very much.
It's close, but I'm glad
we chose Kinugawa.
We can take it easy.
I wonder what that was all about
when Saiko and Hattori left
the ceremony together.
That again?
When I ask Saiko, he kept
saying "It was nothing."
Anyway,
let's enjoy our honeymoon!
All right?
Oh, I like this show!
This may be a bit abrupt,
but do you read manga?
Yes, I read a lot of it.
One Piece, Naruto,
Inumaru Dashi, and Crow!
That's the one!
Our guest today is
the creator of Crow
with a successful anime to boot.
Mangaka Niizuma Eiji!
Tada!
No way!
Hello?
Saiko!
Turn on the TV!
Huh?
Channel 2!
What's this all about?
We'd like to ask you what goes on behind the scenes of manga production.
Glad to answer.
Isn't it difficult to work on two
simultaneous weekly serializations?
Aside from sleeping, eating, and
going to the bathroom, I'm drawing.
So you're always drawing?!
Yes.
I'm happiest when
drawing manga.
Now then,
we've drawn up what a weekly
schedule looks like for Niizuma!
Not just his work,
but he himself is popular!
But still, aren't there times
when you just want to toss aside your manuscript and have fun?
Is there a weak part of yourself that you're fighting against?
Like, you're your own worst enemy?
No, my enemy...
My rival...
is Ashirogi Muto!
Ashirogi Muto?
They are the mangakas I like most,
and my rivals.
You don't know them?
Er, no, I'm sorry.
I'm not knowledgeable enough.
Well then, the next question...
What kind of music do you like?
Mashiro?!
Dammit!
Mashiro?
Azuki.
I want to quit Tanto!
What do you mean?
Tanto's no good!
It has no future!
What do you mean?
Is it because of our promise
that you want to quit?
No.
Of course I want to fulfill
the promise I made to you.
But right now, I want to quit...
because I want to aim higher!
I want to compete
with Niizuma Eiji!
Niizuma Eiji was on TV.
He doesn't read Tanto anymore.
Although that's what he said,
he just clearly stated
that we're his rivals!
Mashiro.
I also think you should quit.
If a person you think of as your rival will go that far for you, then you should quit.
It's frustrating isn't it?
Have you told Takagi yet?
I can't tell him.
He's married and has
to support his family.
I can't just say "Let's quit!"
I can only say
that if it were me, I would quit.
And if we were married
and you said you wanted to quit, I'd agree without a second thought.
Thanks.
I'll talk to Shuujin when he
gets back from his vacation.
I want to thank you too, Mashiro.
You've confided in me.
And by phone too.
Right.
We said we'd talk to each
other about anything...
Yes.
We're maturing.
Our love is growing.
Talk to you later, then.
Try your best, and cheer up!
I love you.
Niizuma speaks better than I expected.
He might actually turn out to be popular.
He might be in demand
for variety shows.
Two serializations and
public appearances, huh?
It's kinda complicated.
Huh?
Well, there's no point
in comparing them,
but yesterday, I got a phone
call from Nakai's mother.
The guy who went back
home to the country?
She thanked me again and again
for looking after her son.
It was tough.
He only got one
serialization, after all.
It's all good if it sells,
but we can't take
responsibility if it doesn't.
We're in positions that control the direction of people's lives.
We should always
keep that in mind.
You want to quit?!
Quit Tanto's serialization?
Yeah.
It's true that our
ratings haven't gone up,
but we don't have to quit...
Before that, we should
work on improving it.
That would be fine too.
Then which one is it?
I can't be selfish.
I know you want to keep going.
I also think we can't
surpass Eiji with Tanto.
I felt pathetic when I heard him
declare that we were his rivals.
That was the final blow for me.
Hearing from Hattori
that we could surpass
Eiji didn't help, either.
Let's quit.
Quit?
Are you serious?
I'm serious.
Actually, you were the
one who said it first.
Don't act so shocked.
Have you thought about Kaya?
You're married now, Shuujin.
Kaya said that you and I make
the decisions about work.
When Tanto was serialized,
I definitely didn't
want to lose to Iwase,
but now losing is just
a normal occurrence.
It's too pathetic.
But I don't think they'll
let us quit just like that.
Huh?
If the author really wants to quit, they have to let us, right?
Wha—
What're you saying?!
This isn't funny!
But we really feel like
there's no future in this.
I'm at my limit for adding humor.
Miura, please tell us.
If the author wants to quit,
will they let us?
Well, I'm saying...
I should take this
to the higher ups...
Don't be ridiculous!
You wanted to be able
to draw in the hospital,
and now you want to quit?
There's a limit to selfishness!
Listen.
Tanto's got the kids' vote.
It's important to us.
Even at its current rank?
Yeah.
You'll have to put in some
work to get the ratings up,
but it's not in danger
of being canceled.
The question is how to get it higher.
They say they're at
their limit for jokes.
That's your job!
A manga was canceled so
that Tanto could get in.
You should have more
pride in your work.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
May I ask the Chief Editor
for his opinion, as well?
Just give up.
You'll only get scolded.
Then I'll go get scolded.
Hey—
Saiko!
What is it?
I would like to quit the
serialization of Tanto.
If you want to quit, then quit.
I have no need for authors who throw aside their work in the middle of a serialization.
You won't draw for Jack anymore.
If you are prepared for
that, then you may quit.
Figured as much.
What's wrong?
Were you not prepared for that?
Prepared, huh.
What should we do, Shuujin?
Should we stay fixated
on Jack and keep going...
or quit?
Hey, what are you saying?!
Of course you'll keep going!
I'm sorry, Saiko.
I want to beat Niizuma Eiji and
Akina Aiko in Jack, at the very least.
I also want to win
against Niizuma Eiji.
But I can't do that with Tanto.
Is this talk about Niizuma
coming from his declaration
of you as his rivals on TV?
Yes!
Do you think you can win
against him if you quit Tanto
and write another work?
It isn't that I think we can win,
it's that I want to win!
Chief Editor, this is my fault!
Since they debuted,
I've kept saying that Ashirogi
Muto can overcome Eiji,
and again, recently,
at Takagi's wedding...
Ashirogi Muto can overcome Niizuma Eiji?
Niizuma's proclamation,
then this...
It seems there is a problem within the editing department.
Takagi, do you think
that you can surpass Niizuma Eiji with a work other than Tanto?
I don't think it's possible.
Excuse me, but...
I believe they have
the talent to do so,
but they haven't been
able to utilize it yet.
Vice-Chief!
Of course, I believe
they can as well.
If they don't go mainstream.
Me too!
I'm asking Takagi.
We'll beat Niizuma Eiji!
So please let us end Tanto!
Shuujin.
The contract is for the full year, right?
How many more serialization
committees are there?
Three more.
The beginning of August,
the middle of October,
and end of December.
If you let us quit,
then Mashiro and I will definitely
submit something to
one of those committees
that can compete with Niizuma Eiji!
If we can't, then you
can end our contract!
We won't draw for Jack anymore!
You said before...
that saying you're not being allowed to draw what you like
is admitting that you have no talent.
Then we'll submit something to one of those three committees
that the entire editorial
department can approve of!
Is that fine with you, Mashiro?
Yes!
I see.
But it's not something that
falls under my responsibility.
Your editor is Miura.
Miura, please!
Please!
Miura!
Let's win against Niiuzma!
Thank you!
They actually did it.
But...
They raised the bar too
high for themselves.
Now they really...
might not be able to
draw for Jack any more.
toomawari wo eranda no wa
The reason I chose to take a detour
motto kimi wo suki ni naru tame datta n da
was to fall ever deeper in love with you
boku no namae yobu sono koe wo
I have a feeling I've always known
zutto zutto shitteta ki ga shita n da
what your voice sounds like when it calls my name
boku no yubisaki de egaita
With my fingertips I drew
subete no sen wa kimi ni tsuzuku kakehashi sa
many lines that make up a suspension bridge leading to you
(Show me the way) bokura no michi kitto
(Show me the way) I'm sure our path
(Believe in your way) hitosuji ni tsunagari
(Believe in your way) connects us without any turns
(Show me the way) yakusoku no basho e tsuzuku
(Show me the way) It leads to the place where we promised
(Show me the way) akirametari shinaide
(Show me the way) I will never give up
(Believe in your way) sono hitomi wo agete
(Believe in your way) Raise your gaze
(Show me the way) bokura wa massugu deau sa
(Show me the way) and see that we're certain to meet again
Next
Episode
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
We need to make our next work
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
something that can
compete with Niizuma Eiji!
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
Money
Intelligence
Appearance
How about a cute female
protagonist who marries a mangaka?
No way.
Next time on Bakuman:
Selfishness and
Advice
Selfishness and Advice.
Sometimes detours and byways become the path to your dream!