La La La
Otter Otter Otter Otter
Rakko Rakko Rakko Rakko
Otter Otter Otter No. 11
Rakko Rakko Rakko 11-gou
No. 1 has a little long beard
1-gou choppiri hige nagari
No. 2 has some really nice fur
2-gou kenami ga ii teidou
No. 3 has really big ears No. 4 has a wide chest
3-gou fukumimi	4-gou hatomune
No. 5 has some really charming eyes
5-gou memoto ga chaamingu
No. 6 has tried some manicure
6-gou manikyua nuttemita
No. 7 has tried some pedicure
7-gou pedikyua nuttemita
No. 8 & 9 have absolutely no records
8-gou 9-gou kiroku nashi
No. 10 has a two-metre long tail!
10-gou shippo ga nii meetoru
And No. 11 We are No. 11
Soshite 11-gou warera ga 11-gou
Otter Otter Otter Otter
Rakko Rakko Rakko Rakko
Otter Otter Otter No. 11
Rakko Rakko Rakko 11-gou
Well-done beefsteaks are my very favorite food!
Koubutsu bifuteki uerudan