Thursday, January 2nd
First chapter name...
Complete!
It's way better than before!
Yeah, even I can tell!
Shuujin, let Hattori know.
Right!
In only five days,
they've redone it from
scratch and taken it this far!
It's much better!
Oh thank goodness.
I suppose you two
didn't get much sleep?
So,
how else can we fix it?!
Can it get better?!
So that it can definitely beat Niizuma!
Let's see.
Is the title okay as is?
Perfect Crime Club...
It may be a bit stiff.
Yeah...
It should be more
shounen manga-like.
Well, there's the tried-and-true method of putting the protagonist's name in the title.
Like Captain Tsubasa?
Yeah.
Tanto was like that too.
Tanto
That way you know right away what it's about and who's the main character.
It's certainly easy to tell from that,
and it's simple and easy to remember.
If that's the case, then...
Chimitsu Kei
"Chimitsu Kei" doesn't leave much of an impression.
It may be too plain for a main character.
Oozora Tsubasa.
Sakuragi Hanamichi.
You want a well-defined name with as much impact as those.
A name suitable for
a main character...
Speaking of main characters,
there's one more
thing you need to fix.
One more thing?
A design suitable for
a main character.
Since the setting calls for a
normal elementary school kid,
we want it to be realistic,
so to a certain degree it's okay,
but he's just too normal right now.
There's no difference between
him and his classmates.
The impact of his appearance...
This is more important
than his name, isn't it?
You're right.
He needs to have a
special characteristic.
I'll do his character design.
Takagi, you worry about
the name and the title.
Let's redo all the main
characters' names, not just his.
Got it.
I'll think of them as soon as I can.
I've given them all the advice I can.
You don't have to hurry with the names, since we can just cut and paste them in.
I'll leave the rest to them.
But the character design needs to come first, so I have to hurry.
I've got you two assistants.
I've made sure they're
suited to your art style.
Oh, and we've got
Orihara on board too.
Counting backwards...
We'll make it if we start the
manuscript around the 13th.
The 13th is the New Year's party.
Oh, right.
If we have a new serialization,
we have to go, don't we?
The New Year's party.
I want to do what
my uncle couldn't do,
and the things he left undone.
What he couldn't do?
What he left undone?
What he couldn't do
was make a living
off of manga alone.
What he left undone
was getting first
place in the survey!
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Votes and Charts
Monday, January 13th
Is the coming of age
ceremony over already?
How could I let you keep
working alone when I haven't
come up with character
names or a title yet?
Iwase and Ishizawa were there too,
so we ducked out early.
But you've really drawn a lot of them.
There must be a hundred.
I've drawn everything I could think of.
Is there one that jumps out at you?
You're the one who knows
the most about art.
I'm good with whatever
you come up with.
I haven't come up with anything yet, which is why I'm still drawing.
Since we want to keep things realistic,
there's a limit to what
I can do with the hair.
I don't want an elementary
school kid looking like that.
I know!
I guess we can't go to today's
New Year's party, after all.
Oh, it's Abe!
We saw each other at the ceremony.
Hey!
Yeah.
I'm not home yet.
Huh? Right now?
Both of us?
Ashirogi isn't coming?
What a shame.
They're working hard, aren't they?
I'm happy.
I can't believe they'd give up this brief time of enjoyment.
So...
What's up with that outfit, Akira?
It's punishment for the editors whose authors didn't show up.
And you, Yuujirou?
Fukuda is still
drawing his manuscript.
Boss Fukuda isn't here either?!
What are these people thinking?
Hiramaru.
We'll have to work harder too.
Let the hardworking folks work hard.
Meanwhile, I can take a break.
I'm living large with these Otter figures selling like pancakes!
Do you want one too?
An Otter figure—
Aoki!
Hiramaru-sensei, I misjudged you.
You are conceited.
Hey—
I was just joking!
Hey, wait!
You got what you
deserved, Hiramaru.
Akina-sensei!
Happy New Year!
Congratulations.
Your latest manuscript was fantastic.
I'm counting on you for the rest.
Of course it is.
I will become the
best in the business.
I'm expecting art that's even better than your usual quality.
Roger!
The editor swap put
a fire under Akina.
We've got some powerful
rivals, Ashirogi Muto!
Akira!
Yuujirou.
It looks like you're up.
Are we seriously doing this?
And now, the moment
you've all been waiting for!
Next up is the Hattori combo,
Giraffe Akira and Zebra
Yuujirou with Otters 11!
Hello?
It's Mashiro.
I'm sorry we couldn't make
it to the New Year's party.
Don't sweat it, this is
part of an editor's job.
Thanks to that, I've finished
the character design!
Oh, really?
I'll be going back to the office.
Can you send me a fax?
Yes.
The phone strap idea is good.
The way he changes modes
with glasses isn't forced.
It's good!
I'm glad!
Put this in the manuscript right away.
Right!
It's been a while!
Nice to be working with you again!
You too.
Sorry we made you wait for half a year.
What are you talking about?
I've grown over this past year,
and I'm ready to
bust my tail for you!
The new assistants will be
here soon, won't they?
Right.
Moriya and Shiratori, right?
He said they're both
younger than us, I think.
It's the first time our
assistants will all be younger.
I'm getting kind of nervous.
Because you're shy, Saiko.
Oh right, about this Moriya guy...
Kyojingai Hourou
Moriya Shuuichi                      (19) Tokyo
So he was a finalist for the
most recent Tezuka prize.
That's some strange art.
But it's good.
He has design sense.
I couldn't find anything on Shiratori.
They're here!
This is Moriya.
He's one year
younger than you two.
He was attending design school,
but after he was a finalist
for the Tezuka prize,
he left to draw manga.
Yes.
If I'm aiming to be a mangaka,
I figured it would be quicker
if I start out as an assistant.
This is Shiratori.
He just graduated from
high school last year.
He applied to be an
assistant for Niizuma,
but his assistants had
already been decided on,
so I brought him over here.
I didn't get in to art school and was wondering what I was going to do...
when I saw the
recruitment for assistants.
I love drawing, so I'm glad.
You haven't actually drawn
any manga before, right?
Right.
But I like reading them.
I guarantee their skill.
Looking forward to
working with you.
You too.
We're counting on you.
Mashiro.
Yes?
This is your third serialization.
You can take it from here, right?
Yes!
Then I'll get going.
Good evening!
Th-Then...
I'm going to give you
each a copy of two pages
of the manuscript with a rough sketch of the backgrounds.
Please draw it in.
I'll choose one of you to do backgrounds
so that the style doesn't
change from page to page.
So only one of us
will be able to draw?
Sounds good to me.
Okay, I'll do my best.
Skill is a given,
but they need speed
and sense too...
I'm finished.
What?
Me too.
What?!
Please look over it.
Okay,
But I'll only decide once
Orihara is finished.
I understand.
I'm done!
Even I'm getting nervous.
Yeah.
I'd like to ask...
Shiratori to do backgrounds.
Yay, I get to draw!
That's great, Shiratori!
Congrats!
Why him?!
His art is nearest to
what I imagined.
Until the style of this
manga is solidified,
I'll have Shiratori do it.
I understand.
Anyway, this Perfect
Crime Club is really good!
Yeah, I like how it's unique.
The title's still a placeholder. I'm planning on changing it.
The main character's name too.
Really?
As long as we have the time,
I'm going to keep nitpicking over the details until I'm satisfied.
Well, I don't think the title
and the main character's name will really affect the rankings.
You're really thinking this through.
Rankings, huh.
There's something wrong
about stuff like rankings.
There's no point in drawing
manga just to get popular.
But manga is for
everyone to enjoy, right?
Popularity is important.
You can't draw a good
manga if you think like that!
Though since you don't draw any manga,
I suppose it has nothing to do with you.
Then what's your ideal manga?
To me, manga is a form of
self-expression and a fine art.
I believe all manga should be thus.
Fine art, huh?
If you do it that way, you'll feel good about yourself, but it won't sell.
Jack is a business,
so the manga has to appeal
to a majority of people.
Isn't it obvious that rankings
and sales figures are important?
To try and draw for Jack
without understanding that...
Shiratori, you've gone too far!
Saiko...
Please tell us
your opinion.
We are trying to get this to sell.
But that's because we
don't have the talent.
Parents used to say to their kids...
well, maybe they're still saying this...
"Reading manga makes you stupid."
They wouldn't let them read it.
But manga gradually came to be recognized as having cultural value.
That's why I think you should draw a manga with content
and quality that you wouldn't be ashamed to say has cultural value.
But since we don't have
the ability to do that,
we have to draw it
with popularity in mind.
I think it's okay for anyone
to draw manga like that,
in accordance with their abilities.
Yes, everyone should
draw in their own way.
Good work, Mashiro.
Oh, thanks.
I didn't know what was going to happen during that argument!
Well, it looks like they're at opposite ends of the spectrum.
It's hard to say
who's right or wrong.
Opposites, huh?
Opposite?!
I could turn this around...
I was too caught up with
the idea of a perfect crime.
If I think along the lines of them not committing real crimes, then...
What's he saying?
I've got it!
How about this?!
Doumoto Makoto
Tokunaga Minoru
If you put them together, that's "morals" and "truth."
They fit the main characters,
since they're the opposite of "crime."
Doumoto Makoto.
Tokunaga Minoru.
And Annojo Mai!
They're not bad!
They're kinda cool, even!
They're great.
Let's go with that!
You're awesome, Akito!
This is what happens when
I get a flash of intuition.
So what about the title?
I haven't got that yet.
That's disappointing.
Well, we still have a few days
before we need to finish.
It's a perfect manuscript!
The story and art are a given,
but the protagonist's
names are good too!
And this title—
Perfect
Crime
Party.
PCP!
The Japanese translation is "Perfect Crime Party."
Perfect Crime Party
Right!
I was watching the news
and I thought "party" as in "political party" would work well.
"Party" has a cheerful image,
and since it's also used in video games, I thought it would make it seem fun.
A typical Takagi analysis.
The effort you two put
into this really shows.
Yes!
We'll definitely get first
place for the first chapter!
We've put everything we possibly could into this to accomplish that!
I think aiming for that with this manuscript is more than reasonable.
The rest depends on Fukuda's one-shot, since that'll be in the issue too.
Fukuda's one-shot?
I didn't hear about this!
This is why I said it was impossible to do a one-shot and Kiyoshi at the same time!
You gave me your permission!
That's why I'm helping you right now!
But this manga is good!
It's on fire!
Road Racer Buchigiri.
There was a super car boom.
Now I'll cause a super bike boom!
It's not bad to have a hobby.
It's all because you
said that to me, Yuujirou.
I'm grateful to you for that.
Well, thanks a bunch!
But I'm pissed that it's in the same issue as Ashirogi's first chapter!
It means they want to compare it with a new serialization.
The editorial department
put some thought into it.
I feel sorry for Ashirogi Muto!
I'll steal the top spot
from them with this!
Tuesday, February 11th
This is the finished sample copy.
It sure is nice to be
on the front cover.
Fukuda's manga is good.
It feels like a straightforward shounen.
He drives by girls on
purpose to flip up their skirts.
Typical Fukuda.
Both his characters and
story are typical mainstream.
I think it's good too.
Mainstream...
This is gonna split the votes.
Fukuda's on a roll.
Making a manga about your
hobby sure has a big effect.
But if it comes down
to a new serialization
and a one-shot, people are more likely to vote for the new serialization, right?
That trend does exist,
but it's not a sure thing.
Buchigiri has a clear goal of becoming the number one racer.
The race scenes are
showy and intense.
PCP has a lot of exposition
and will look plain in comparison.
But the content is good, right?
Yes, it is.
Then...
That is, if they
understand what's going on.
The majority of the
readers are in their teens.
Buchigiri is easier for
them to understand.
Aida, what ranking do
you think PCP will get?
If it splits votes with Buchigiri,
then it may be hard for it to get ahead of the other popular manga.
It's all up to the readers.
Monday, February 17th
Hey, the early results
are in tomorrow, right?
I've told him to only let
us know the final results.
What? But I really want to know!
Rankings, huh?
Moriya, not again—
I would like to know as well.
I hope it does well.
Me too.
It definitely will!
That's right.
PCP is the manga
that must rank highly.
Will we place even with Niizuma?
Or even higher?
Friday, February 21st
I can't seem to calm down.
Hey, what time will the
final results be out?
Judging from last time, the call could come as late as 5 PM.
Mashiro, what time are
your assistants coming?
4:30.
I hope he contacts us
before they get here.
Then let's try calling him!
They may be out already!
He'll contact us as
soon as they're out.
Just calm down.
But...
I read it!
I thought it was really good!
I especially liked the part where they spent two weeks preparing
and in just one night,
made a message with
flowers in the flower bed.
I wish someone would do that for me.
It'll be okay.
See, the assistants came already!
What?
It's not even 4 yet.
Hattori?
I'm astonished.
It's the best by far.
422 votes.
A 150 vote lead over 2nd place.
1st place.
Hey, the door's open!
Yes!
We did it! We did it!
We did it!
Yeah, we did it!
We got first place!
By a landslide!
You did it, Saiko!
Let me in too!
We did it!
Print
Rank
Manga
Votes
Author
PCP -Perfect Crime Party-
Ashirogi Muto
Fukuda Shinta
Road Racer Buchigiri
422 votes... we haven't seen that since Crow!
Crow got 401.
And back then, there
was no one-shot.
It got even more than +Natural did with its recent 1st place.
Natural only got 310 votes!
If there wasn't a one-shot,
how would it have done?
Anyway, it's amazing.
2nd place with 268 votes?
Yeah, Ashirogi was just
too overwhelming.
That's frustrating.
But it's a great vote tally.
Fukuda Shinta should make Buchigiri.
That's what the readers want.
You can wrap up Kiyoshi.
Make a serialization
name for Buchigiri!
Wow, isn't that great?
I got beat pretty bad by Ashirogi.
I'll pay them back
with a serialization!
They did?
Yes, and by a landslide.
+Natural dropped to 8th place.
This was only because PCP
and Buchigiri were good...
I'll rewrite it.
Huh?
I cannot afford to lose
to Takagi and Hattori.
I'll rewrite everything you haven't sent to the printer yet!
Niizuma
Eiji  Ltd.
So she said she wants to
rewrite as much as possible.
Even what I'm drawing now?
Yes, if possible...
Akina-sensei said she'll
make it better, right?
That's right.
Roger!
If she wasn't that fired
up, I'd be disappointed!
If we don't make it better,
Ashirogi will overtake us!
akirame wa shinai dare ni mo watasenai
I won't give up on it, won't be persuaded
Under 10 and over 18?
Yeah.
The main demographic voted too,
but those two age ranges
were particularly conspicuous.
kono yume dake wa kakegaenai mono
My dream is the one irreplaceable thing
Let's analyze that and use
it for reference going forward.
All right!
Let's set aside the
difficult issues for now,
kuyashinamida nara gutto korareta ano hi
The chagrin I've felt I always bore with pride
since Hattori went out of
his way to bring us a feast!
Before I realized it,
I was at the grocery store...
kodoku no kazu dake purasu ni kaeteku sutoorii
This story will change all my solitude into something positive
Hattori.
Can I have the results chart?
No.
norikoetemo sugu arata na genjitsu
Even if we rise above our life, a different one awaits us
Even though you're an author,
I can't give it to you.
Do you want it as a keepsake?
No, I have someone
I want to show it to.
kirihiraiteyuku mirai kono te de
I will cut a path for my future
Then I really can't give it to you.
Other authors' rankings are on here.
I have no problem with
you telling your own
rank to others, though.
kokoro no oku mamoritai yume ga aru kara
Inside my heart lies a dream I wish to protect
Then...
Would you come with me?
shinjiteyuke oi kaze ni notte
so I can go on believing, and chasing the wind
Okay.
mezasu basho wa tada hitotsu kimi to waraitai
There is only one place I have my eyes set on: where we can laugh together
Is it okay for me to come too?
There's no point if
we aren't together.
boku ni takushitekureta yume he tsunagaru hikari
There lies a light that connects to the dream you gave me
This is...
kimi wo tsureteku kara mada minu ashita he ima
I will lead you towards a future neither of us is aware of yet
Uncle...
Dream of Life
This is what you wanted,
but never managed to get.
A first place ranking
in Weekly Shounen Jack.
furikaeru to tashika na ashiato ga
When I look back I see my footsteps
ikutsumo no nayami yorokobi de dekiteita
made by countless moments of happiness and sorrow
kyou made ikita boku nari no akashi wa tsuyosa he
This proof that I have lived until today is what lends me strength
mune ni kizami mae he fumidashiteku n da
I will engrave it into my chest and walk forward with proud strides
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga aru kara
I have a dream I want to see through
moyashiteyuke jounetsu wo atsuku
I can alight my passion, set fire to it
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
As we pursue our dreams, we will meet and split
It's not like I got
this all by myself.
kimi ga oshiete kureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
You taught me a strength only I wield
Many people helped me.
But Ashirogi Muto got 1st place!
tachiagatteku n da yo nando tsumazuita tte
I will stand up, go on, no matter how often I stumble
So what if your first
chapter got first place?
Of course it would.
Dream of Life
Back when Fist of the
North Star was popular,
it got first place with
more than 700 votes.
The real challenge
starts from here, right?
When you get really popular
and are truly number one,
come back here.
Of course I will!
Six months.
We'll see how it goes
until their 25th chapter.
If they get such low rankings
that it should be canceled, then after their 7th chapter, I won't hesitate.
And if they aren't head to head
with Crow and
+Natural by chapter 25,
I'll cancel it right then and there.
We managed to get
1st place in the rankings,
but the anime still goes on!
Can Ashirogi Muto make
their dreams come true?
Bakuman Season 3!
Please watch it!