Don't rush and take it slowly, huh.
But being told that gets
me even more fired up.
I hope you're not feeling that way just because Azuki said that.
Isn't that fine?
Even Miyoshi was...
Cheer up! On to the next one!
...like that.
She doesn't get that the more pressure I'm under, the less I want to work.
She's not wrong.
You're already feeling better and thinking about the next one, right?
Our next one, huh.
The next work after a serialization is both important and difficult.
Yeah.
I'm kinda jealous of Koogy, since he's still being serialized in Jack SQ.
And we can't even touch Eiji.
But we can't lose.
Let's do our best to
surpass him this time.
Yeah!
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight won't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come to achieve that?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years time I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, ensuring I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again
Dream of Life
Gag and Serious
Start out with a one-shot?
Yeah.
We'll try things out with a one-shot,
and if it's popular,
a serialization will follow.
Awfully cautious of you.
Is it because Azuki told
you to take it slow?
That's not it.
If we have two serializations
fail, that's it for us.
So we'll tread carefully.
Just to be certain, huh?
It would be ideal if our
one-shot came in second
like Takahama's Business Boy Kenichi so that we could start a serialization name from there.
First, we need to put out a decent one-shot.
We don't have school, so let's sleep on it.
For college, I'm thinking of Yana College's business school.
Business school?
That's got nothing to do with us.
I wouldn't even pass the entrance exam.
It's only two subjects,
English and Japanese,
and I could help you, so
there wouldn't be a problem.
I see.
Have you told Miyoshi about this?
Oh, sure, I'll go.
Tutor me!
O-Okay, starting tomorrow.
Miura, don't you have any names for the next serialization meeting?
Uh, no.
Sorry.
Takahama's can't make
the February meeting...
Ashirogi and Takahama...
You've got two golden eggs there.
You'd better shape up.
Golden eggs, huh?
Certainly, anyone can see that they're a cut above the rest of the newbies.
I have to get them serialized soon...
I think we should take the safe route
by trying things out
with a one-shot first.
Huh?
What's with that, Mashiro?
That's not like you.
It's obvious that you need to get serialized as soon as possible.
The editorial department and your fans are all expecting great things from Ashirogi Muto.
If you're gonna do it,
aim for serialization!
Even if you make a
one-shot and it's popular,
that's entirely different from having a completed serialization name.
Even if I tell the editorial department that you should make a one-shot to test an idea,
you should still be drawing
with serialization in mind.
Leave the decision to us, and just draw a serialization name.
Okay!
Shuujin?
But right now we have
no idea what to draw...
Oh, right.
I think your next work should be...
a gag manga.
Gag?!
There's no way...
Yeah!
Why?
When you put more jokes into the last two chapters of Trap,
Survey Rankings        Shady Detective Trap
they both came in 13th place.
That's true, but it only
rose from 17th to 13th.
Getting to 13th from down
there is a pretty big deal.
The word plays were really good too.
Takagi has a pretty good feel for jokes.
I do?
Yeah!
Your humor can be your weapon!
You've got to make use of it.
No.
That's not where Shuujin's talent lies.
Jokes, huh?
Right now, Jack's popular manga are mostly serious and battle manga.
It's best to assume that if you try beating them at their own game, you'll lose.
I see.
That's definitely...
No.
This isn't something good to try!
We're not seeing eye-to-eye anymore!
Miura's no good.
He isn't?
Why not?
We should definitely make a one-shot that could potentially
get serialized instead of
a serialization name!
Aren't they basically the same thing?
Hattori!
You sure are working hard, even though your serialization just ended.
If you were in our position,
would you go straight for
a serialization name...
or do a one-shot with serialization in mind?
Hey, Saiko!
It's a tough question,
but your editor is Miura.
I shouldn't be giving my
opinion while he isn't around.
All I can say is that it's okay to disagree with your editor.
That's it.
See you.
Thank you.
Miura just likes humor.
We can't just do what he says.
But Miura is really helping us out.
Yes, he is!
He's working as hard
as if it were for himself!
But it won't work out if we're going in the wrong direction!
Keep your voice down!
Shuujin.
Are you planning on
doing what he asks?
Well, when he mentioned gags, I felt like he was wrong...
But then I got carried away with it...
Right?
Well, this isn't the time to act cool.
Oh, Takagi-sensei.
Goo' efeningh.
Niizuma!
I'm asking this as your rival!
Do you want to read a gag manga written by Ashirogi Muto?
I'll rea' anyfing writt'n
by Afirogi Muto, but...
But?
More than humor, what really draws out your appeal is a harsh story.
I want to read a harsh story
written by Ashirogi Muto.
Thank you.
He said a "harsh" story.
"Harsh?"
What does that even mean?
Money and Intelligence.
I've received it.
That, huh?
It was harsh and it did
rank higher than Eiji's,
even if it was only in the early results.
Hattori said that kind
of story suits us too.
This isn't good.
It feels like Miura's wrong.
That's why I'm saying
we should dispute this.
We've got no choice but to fight Miura with what we feel is right.
Nakai
This is Nakai.
Hello.
Are you thinking
about your next work?
No.
I don't think I'm writing
for Jack anymore...
What do you mean,
you're not writing for Jack?
I think I will draw my
own shoujo manga.
That's...
Won't you work with me again?
Your art is wonderful,
and I think you have a lot of talent.
You should illustrate a story that will make better use of your art.
I want to work on your manuscript.
It doesn't have to be me...
In fact,
I think it would be better if it wasn't me.
Why are you so fixated on me?
Th-That's...
Because I love you!
I respect you...
as a creator of great
art, and as a mangaka.
But I'm sorry.
As a man...
This is Yamahisa from
Weekly Shounen Jack.
Yes?
Haven't you heard from Aida yet?
I'm your new editor.
I was thinking about
arranging a meeting soon...
Well, I think I'm finished with Jack...
What are you saying?
That's such a waste!
I read your one-shot for Magnolia.
Let's do one like that for Jack.
I was touched by the way your art portrayed the feelings of those in love.
It'll definitely sell!
A love story in Jack?
Yes!
As long as you have at least three panty shots a week, it'll be fine.
Definitely! It'll definitely be popular!
There are always some manga in Jack that are a bit raunchy.
It's always an essential
and in-demand genre.
Please believe me!
Let's do it!
Aida, did you not tell Aoki
about the editor switch?
Didn't we decide yesterday?
We're waiting to tell
her while I look into it.
Well, I already told her.
She's going to stay with Jack!
It's great!
I wanna read it!
Well, new editors
should be a bit reckless.
Compared to that...
Miura!
Were you paying attention to that?
If you keep fooling around,
you'll be overtaken soon!
Hurry up and submit
Ashirogi Muto's contract!
Even I'm starting to feel pressure from the higher-ups about it!
Oh, sorry.
I just forgot...
"Just forgot?"
Come on!
I-I'll get them to sign it soon!
Why do Japanese people
have to study English?
Shut up!
Stop whining like a
little brat and get to it!
Scary!
You've been in a
crazy bad mood lately!
It's Miura!
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
Sorry to do this while you're trying to study.
It's fine.
So, lets take care of the contract.
Um, before that...
I don't think a gag
manga would suit us.
I told you, the rankings don't lie.
It does suit you.
I want to go with a serious feel.
With humor where it feels appropriate.
Huh?
Have you drawn
something serious already?
No, not yet.
Then just do as I tell you!
I'm the editor!
I'm not pulling this out of my ass!
Gag
In cases where an author starts a new work after their serialization has ended,
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
even if their previous work was a big hit, they need to change their literary style.
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
Feudal era
Futuristic
School life
Sports
Serious
Gag
We will change our style.
But I don't believe humor
highlights Takagi's strengths.
Are you saying I'm wrong?!
Yes!
If the authors don't trust the editor, they can't work well together!
I think so too!
Two...
We'll create two works!
A humorous one and a serious one!
It's unheard of to submit two
serialization names,
especially if it's at the same time!
I can only submit one!
So if we finish two,
we have to get someone
else to look at them?
Do you really have so little
trust in my eye for manga?
Submitting two works and asking them which they think is better...
There's no way I could
do something so pitiful!
Hey, hey.
If you're going to shout,
do it in the lobby.
I-I apologize.
This wouldn't be happening
if Hattori was our editor...
Fine.
Give me two serialization names within the first ten days of March.
Each of them three chapters long.
In other words, six chapters.
I won't pass out half-assed
names at the meeting.
Understood?
Yes.
It feels like we just
made things worse.
We should stick with doing
what we want to do though.
Even if it means fighting Miura.
We're already halfway there in that respect.
I see!
If it's okay to fight with him...
Huh? What is it?
We still have a hand to play.
What?
You're quitting studying?!
There's only one week
till the entrance exam!
Right now, this is more important.
Now stop bothering us!
Hey Shuujin, you really are amazing.
How did you come up with this idea?
They mysteriously pop into my head when I'm under pressure!
It's like a switch was turned on!
It came from doing Trap.
The knack for writing names just suddenly came to me!
"Two of Me."
This is pretty cool.
Show it to me!
Whaaa?!
A
Me?
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
Who are you?
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
Who
are you?
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
No, who are you ?
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
A
Who
are you?
Face and pose
are the same
...are you
me?
A
Are you me?
Did I split
into two?
Did I split into two?
A
We should make use
of this situation
effectively!
We should make use of
this situation effectively!
A
But what good is
if our thoughts
and actions are
exactly the same?
Ok, when this pencil falls,
whoever it's pointing
towards has to leave.
No way!
You!
I've
got
it!!
No, wait,
i should take
advantage of this.
You!
We have to
decide this some
other way.
Of course
we're gonna
say the same
thing in a fight.
Wait,
wait.
You're
me.
Once we're apart, we'll have
to make sure not to get
hurt or sunburned or anything.
If we're not exactly alike,
what's the use in there being
two of us?
...We can figure
that out once we
decide who's going
to go we'll probably
just say the same
thing, so it'll be easy
to decide.
But
where
will we
go and
where will
we live?
But which
of us should
move out...?
That's not
a bad idea
we'll live
apart for a while
and then
meet up again...
Isn't this kinda sci-fi ish?
It's like you, and it's interesting!
Yeah, I want to read the rest of it.
Will this be our gag submission?
No, I think this one
should be serious.
Huh?
And I've already got the
gag one all planned out.
Wow!
What kind of story is it?
I call it Hitman 10.
A multi-millionaire searches out the world's top ten hitmen
and offers them a huge
reward to kill each other.
If even one of them takes up the offer,
the others don't know
when they might be killed,
so all of them have to participate.
The main character is a young hitman who's caught up in all of this.
Jumbled together
with professional killers,
it becomes a battle to be number one!
Isn't that pretty serious?
No, since the premise is pretty out there, it'll be easy to put gags in.
You really do have talent.
I'm falling even harder for you!
But my talent will get overshadowed in the world of the pros.
It's a tough market.
So cool!
Ashirogi Muto
_.Yana College Entrance
Examination Hall
I couldn't sleep last night.
_.Yana College Entrance
Examination Hall
It's pointless trying to
cram overnight for a test.
No, I was writing the name.
Hey, now.
We all passed!
Oh, okay.
A college that'll accept you even if you sleep during the exam...
Be a little happier, will you?
You're bringing me down.
Um, Miss Miyoshi?
"Miss?"
Could you do the
inking and tone for me?
Inking on the day we passed...
that'll cost you.
Then I'll pay you 2,000 yen per hour.
I'm just joking.
I wouldn't take
money from you guys.
Miyoshi...
Thanks.
I don't need thanks.
Huh?
Inking and tone...
Aren't you submitting
a name this time?
Why are you preparing a manuscript?
The things people can do
if they put their minds to it...
At any rate, we did what we could.
I'll call Miura.
'Kay.
In Hitman 10...
the jokes were too repetitive and ruined the elaborate setting.
Two of Me
Ashirogi Muto
What really shows
Shuujin's talent, after all...
Wonderful.
Both of them are great.
If we fix them up a bit,
I can confidently present either to the serialization committee.
Either one?
No matter how you
look at it, Two of Me is...
Which one?
Which one will Miura choose?
Ashirogi Muto
Let's aim to serialize Hitman 10!
All right!
This will definitely pass at the meeting.
Let's polish it up.
It's no good.
Takagi definitely has a sense for humor!
He's definitely wrong.
It won't get through to
him no matter what I say.
Ashirogi?
Why did you submit something
to the monthly contest?
The monthly contest?!
I see!
If it's okay to fight with him...
Huh? What is it?
We still have a hand to play.
The monthly contest?
That's a contest for amateurs!
Yeah.
If we submit it here, it'll
get looked at by people
Treasure Rookie
This is J-Treasure's charm!
Examiner for February contest
Niizuma Eiji
Treasure Rookie
This is J-Treasure's charm!
Examiner for February contest
Niizuma Eiji
like the vice-editor in
addition to normal editors.
And Eiji is a judge too!
I trust his judgment
more than Miura's, frankly.
But wouldn't it be bad for
us to go over Miura's head?
Like I said, if we're gonna fight him, we might as well go all out!
Of course, we'll also make
two serialization names.
W-We're making three works?!
Too hard for you?
It's strange.
The more impossible it sounds,
the more fired up I get.
Let's do this.
Three great works!
Let's make them so good, they won't be able to decide which one to serialize!
Yeah!
I didn't hear about this!
What were you thinking
by going over my head?!
We want to try things
out with a one-shot!
Use your common sense!
It's not fair to the other applicants if authors that have already been serialized
enter the monthly competition!
We don't need the prize!
We just want it to be judged!
By Niizuma Eiji!
You're saying that Niizuma has a better eye for manga than me?!
Hey, sit down.
Niizuma's drawing Crow, and you're not drawing anything!
Mashiro, that's going too far.
Hattori.
Why me?
It's a problem between
Miura and Ashirogi.
Miura's still a newbie,
and Ashirogi even more so.
What will you do?
If they insist on it being judged,
I can consult with the Chief.
Before that, we should address
the problem with the authors' attitudes!
Let's start from there!
Miura!
Calm down.
Takagi, Mashiro, think
about Miura's position.
You're not that naive, are you?
B-But...
Do authors really have to do
what the editor tells them?
That's right.
If they have an objection, they need to tell the editor up front.
All manuscripts must
pass through the editor.
All right.
I'll take what you submitted
to the monthly contest
and get it judged, then aim
to get this serialized for you.
What are you saying, Miura?
Tokyo Metropolitan area,
Chiyoda Ward, Hitotsubashi 0-x
Yueisha Weekly Shounen Jack
February Jack Treasure
And if this one-shot
ends up in the magazine
and goes on to become serialized...
I'll quit editing!
Miura...
That's going too far.
There's no problem in saying you'll reflect on your actions,
but saying you'll quit is
just breeding resentment.
You're right.
I apologize.
But it's all right.
I really think Hitman 10 is good.
I'll definitely get this serialized.
Okay.
Then I'll take this up.
Um, sorry for acting on our own.
Really.
It'll be a problem if the serialization name isn't good after all that.
First off, Ashirogi.
"Do not cause any more problems", he says.
Yes.
Well then, in regards
to this manuscript...
It can be submitted for judging, but cannot win the prize.
If it is exceedingly well received,
it will be published in the magazine.
Okay!
Please do so!
However...
If the name submitted to April's serialization committee is no good,
Serialization Name
we won't give priority to this one-shot and won't publish it.
One-shot
If you submit a sound name,
Serialization Name
we'll compare it with the one-shot
One-shot
Serialization Name
and decide which is more
suitable for serialization.
Serialization Name
One-shot
Basically, nothing will happen with your one-shot until after the meeting.
The priority...
is to give your all on the
serialization name!
Yes!
I see.
I'm fine with that.
Let's get Hitman 10 ready
to submit to the committee!
Yes!
First off, lets make this gold-rich
multi-millionaire's character
more exaggerated to make him funnier.
I thought that too, but...
In just a month and a half, they finished two names and a one-shot manuscript...
They haven't changed.
Those two may just be fine as they are.
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
Next
Episode
Future Watch or Hitman 10...
Which will be more popular?
If you worry too much, your jokes will become old geezer jokes.
I know, right?
We're still young.
You old fart.
Next time on Bakuman:
Manga and
Youth
Manga and Youth.
A young man's dreams are hard to achieve!