You slapped Nakai?!
So that means...
there's no going back?
Yes.
I apologize.
No, it's fine.
He wanted you to date him in order to work with him, of all things.
Of course you'd get angry.
But we're in trouble now.
All we need are good female
poses and panty flashes.
I understand.
I'll keep looking for people
who can draw them.
Sounds rough, Yamahisa.
Yeah.
Well, as for me,
I'm lucky that Kiyoshi has
got panty shots in the bag.
Please don't be like that.
Introduce me to someone
who can draw them!
Hirameki
Tanto-kun
Ashirogi Muto
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Prince and Savior
Are you really getting
married if we get serialized?
Yeah.
All this has reminded me of
how much I like Miyoshi,
and made me realize
that I want to be with her.
But you're still only 18!
Enough about that.
They'll be here soon.
Long time no see, Mashiro.
H-Hello.
She went to Miho's place
yesterday to apologize,
and today, she's here.
She's really serious about this.
Yeah, too serious.
I'm not being too serious.
I caused trouble for you all by exchanging ideas with Takagi
without telling Kaya.
That's taking it too seriously.
Um, well, I really...
It's fine, it's fine.
Here, have a seat.
Thank you.
Nakai did that?
You can't work with a guy like that.
I can't even bear to see him now.
So you'll draw Time of Blue
Leaves yourself, then?
Yes.
I will study the kind
of drawings men like,
or get someone who's
good at that to help me.
What are the kinds of
drawings men like?
Well, that's...
Stuff like panty shots.
Right?
Oh, come on.
But guys do like that kind of stuff.
You know, like Kiyoshi.
Fukuda's good at showing underwear.
Yeah, it might be
good to reference him.
I don't want him thinking
I'm using his work as a reference!
Fukuda
Looks good.
We're definitely in the clear
for next week with this.
It doesn't mean much if I can only get votes by putting in panty shots.
Leave this to me.
Good work.
Hey, how'd the results
from Next turn out?
Ashirogi got 1st place.
Oh, they did it!
And Aoki Ko?
She got 2nd, but she's
in a tough spot right now.
Her story's good, but
her art needs work.
Yeah.
This ain't even the most basic of the basics of panty shots.
After some deliberation,
they were going to ask Nakai to do the art for a Jack one-shot, but...
Aoki and Nakai had a fight and it all went to waste, it seems.
A fight?
Fukuda again?
Fukuda Shinta
He'll just rag on me...
The person you have dialed cannot come to the phone at this time.
If you wish to leave a message, please—
It went straight to his voicemail!
What is he thinking?!
Doing a Jack one-shot is
a great chance for him!
If he upset her, all he
has to do is apologize.
All right!
Now that it's come to this,
I'm going on the offensive!
I know he's usually at
Takahama's around now.
I'll come with you!
Just go home!
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
Nakai's out, Fukuda's out...
Is anyone else good
at that kind of art?
There is one other
person who's good at it.
Who?
You know, Ishizawa—
Don't even go there!
Why?
Yes, he is good at that.
But he's out of the question.
Huh?
But...
Anyone but him.
Um, if Mashiro's saying it's good,
it must be quite good, correct?
Yeah, he's got a 3 page slot
in a monthly magazine.
He's not a pro?
He was our classmate
in middle school,
and he happens to go
to the same college—
Hey!
Stop running your mouth.
Give up on him, I'm telling you.
I know you guys hate him, but...
That's not it.
It's his personality
that's the problem.
Even at the best of times,
Aoki is distrustful of men.
I'd like to try meeting him.
What?!
Ishizawa
Takagi?
Why are you calling me?
Just listen.
Ishizawa was all gung-ho.
Yeah, being a Jack author
might not be so bad.
So he said.
Well then, Aoki, shall we go?
Yes.
Hey!
Why is it just you two?
I'm coming, too!
Why?
Well, even if it's just for work, you two would be together...
Okay.
Then you can watch
from a different table.
'Kay.
If it comes down to it, protect Aoki!
Am I the security police?
Yeah.
I'm counting on you.
Uh, okay.
But seriously, Ishizawa?
Will they be okay?
Maybe I should have gone, too.
Fukuda?
Mashiro.
Takahama was your assistant, right?
Yeah.
Where's his office?
Um, I think he works at home.
Then tell me the address.
Sure, but...
did something happen?
Yeah.
I'm gonna get Nakai back on track and make him work with Aoki again.
Huh?
Family Restaurant
Open 24 Hours
So!
I'm the chosen one, eh?
Me, the savior of
Jack author Aoki Ko.
Her prince on a white horse!
He's not joking!
I'm not too interested
in being an assistant.
You'd just be helping her
out with drawing women
in a way that guys like.
In other words, I'll be
her panty-shot guy?
W-Well, yeah.
Fine.
But you'll have to do what I say.
Aoki will make it easy for me.
Just take pictures and movies of yourself in various poses.
I'll sort through them
and decide what's best.
You're not being serious, are you?
Of course I am.
That's the best way to do it, isn't it?
Even so, you shouldn't
talk to a girl like that.
So I should be elegant and
beat around the bush?
That's not my style.
I'm sorry, Aoki.
Asking Ishizawa was a bad idea.
I might have to step in soon.
H-Hey, wait!
Nakai!
Fukuda!
Why are you destroying your
own chance at a one-shot in Jack?!
Stop sticking your nose
where it doesn't belong!
I chose Katou over Aoki.
That's all there is to it.
Are you done?
I'm in the middle of work here.
Don't bother me anymore—
Wh-What the hell are you doing?
When we were
serialized together,
you were glad you didn't give up!
You told me that!
I was happy to be
serialized with you, too!
Because we could compete as rivals!
I won't say not to fall for some girl!
But why aren't you aiming
for serialization anymore?
Have you given up already?
It's...
comfortable here.
Comfortable?
I can see and talk to Katou every day.
That's my happiness!
You guys wouldn't understand!
You could never understand
the feelings of a man
who's never been
popular his entire life!
Don't get in the way of my love life!
You didn't come here
to work, but to date?
No wonder your art
has gotten worse.
Sorry for barging in.
Nakai's useless right now.
But what will happen with Aoki, then?
What exactly do I want to do?
I know that Aoki isn't bending
or changing her opinion.
It may seem cold to other people.
But I think with what I draw,
I can turn it around into
something with passion.
Mashiro.
Wait, Takagi!
You were the one
who asked for my help!
I'm saying I'll cooperate!
I'm sorry it turned out like this.
It's fine...
If Aoki models...
I have to hurry and shut him up.
I know, how about a swimsuit?
I'll draw something great for you!
Aoki, are you listening?
You should think about
what poses are best—
Shut up, Gonzalez!
Her manga doesn't
need to go that far!
I will teach her how
to draw panty shots!
Fukuda!
Why is Fukuda here?
I heard from Mashiro.
Well?
What will you do?
You'll teach her?
What about your own serialization?
I can coach her while drawing.
I can check her rough
sketches through faxes.
In return,
I'll be tougher on her manuscript
than the worst editor.
Fukuda...
Would it be humiliating
to be taught by me?
Well, I suppose so.
Please do.
Ah, okay.
Aoki and Fukuda?
This is a powerful combo...
This is too cruel...
I'm heading out to
meet with Ashirogi.
He doesn't seem too happy, even though Tanto got 1st place.
Business Boy Kenichi hasn't
been doing so well lately.
Hello, this is the Weekly Shounen Jack editorial department.
Hey, Hattori!
You've got a call!
Oh, Taninaka! It's been a while.
You seem to be doing well.
I thought for sure that they'd
be working you to death.
Well, thanks.
You're working at
Novel Pleiades, right?
Yeah, they're working us hard here, but not as hard as you.
Actually,
_Green Graduation
.Akina Aiko
Pleiades Amateur                          Novel Contest Winner
I have a bit of a favor to ask
you, as a former classmate.
A favor?
You're helping out Aoki Ko?
Yeah.
I don't think it's manly
to hide things like this,
so I'm letting you know.
What do you mean by 'helping out'?
I'm primarily coaching
her on panty shots,
but I'll check over her
names through faxes, too.
That's her editor's job!
There are things that mangakas know better than editors.
But do you even have
the luxury to do that?
Kiyoshi is—
I won't let Kiyoshi's popularity drop!
If it does, you'll just
blame me for helping her.
I'll make sure Kiyoshi becomes even more popular than it is now!
How's that for you?!
And don't go thinking I've got feelings for her, or something.
If I had to choose,
I'd say I hate her.
I can't believe you'd go so
far for someone you hate.
She participated in
my boycott, remember?
I'll help her out if
she's in trouble!
It was back when we were
assisting Master Niizuma.
I told this to Mashiro and Nakai:
"We'll change Jack!"
That's so cool!
Don't open the door
without prior
warning! Knock first.
Master Niizuma, Ashirogi Muto, Aoki Ko, Hiramaru Kazuya,
and Nakai Takurou.
With this many of us,
anything's possible!
Change Jack, huh?
Oh yeah, at first, Niizuma said, "If I become the author of the most popular manga,"
"give me the authority
to end one manga I hate!"
The same guy who said that has been apathetic ever since Trap was canceled,
and he's even been overtaken
by Otters 11 recently...
Team Fukuda, huh?
If it raises competition
between the authors, then...
Alright.
I approve of Team Fukuda!
I knew you'd get it, man!
I'm glad I told you!
Hey! Show some more respect!
Could you at least flush, Fukuda?
Do you have a
favorite shounen manga?
Not really.
Do you read a lot of shounen manga?
I've read Jack for
about four years now.
It looks like you attend the
same college as Aoki Ko,
and you also went to
middle school with Ashirogi.
Yes.
May I ask a blunt question?
And that would be?
Do you truly want to write a manga
manuscript to become Takagi's rival?
I heard about it from Taninaka.
You are particularly aware of Takagi.
I won't ask why you
view him as your rival.
But frankly, you're a complete novice when it comes to manga.
If you want to
compete with Takagi,
you'll have to do as I say.
If I listen to you, can I beat him?
We won't know until we try,
but when Takagi and Mashiro first submitted a manuscript,
I was the one who met with them.
A completed manga manuscript
is completely different
from just a written story,
but I feel the same level of talent with you as I did with them back then.
I'm glad.
But this story is based on feelings;
it doesn't have any action, so it will never become a manga.
You have to redo it all.
It will take time.
Are you still willing to do it?
Yes.
Alright then, try marking your work like this to divide it into pages...
for when it's time to draw the art.
I understand.
I'll have it done by tonight.
Well, by tomorrow is fine.
Okay.
She's got spirit.
I think she can do it.
Okay, let's go with
this for chapter one.
I'll put in as many gags as I can think of up until the serialization meeting.
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
Keep going at this pace
for two more chapters.
Anyway, as long as you have three chapters, you'll most likely be serialized.
What do you mean?
There aren't many manuscripts being put up for consideration at the next meeting.
With a 2nd place one-shot in Jack, Arai's Hustlemin Ace is a shoe-in,
and since you were first in Next, you guys are also pretty much guaranteed a spot.
Is that how it is?
Yeah.
Since Aoki's manga got 2nd in Next,
it'll be tried out again
as a Jack one-shot.
So even if the name isn't so great, we'll get serialized anyway?
I definitely want to avoid getting serialized and canceled right away!
That's right!
Let's make a three chapter serialization name that we can all be proud of!
Yes!
For Miyoshi, too!
Yeah.
Well then, let's decide on the invention for the 3rd chapter!
I want to bring in Ms. Noa,
so how about contact lenses that
make clothes look transparent?!
Oh, all guys would want a pair.
But that might be a bit cliché.
Then how about the "Chef Hat"?
While you're wearing it,
any meal, even a school lunch, becomes a three course French dinner!
Oh!
They ask Ms. Noa for help, and have her wear a maid apron.
But the apron makes her want to wait on tables dressed in a miniskirt!
The grandpa, Chotto, wants to see her in the miniskirt and...
That's good.
We still have time.
Let's make it as funny as we can!
Yes!
Would you show me
that list of inventions?
This?
I wrote down whatever popped into my head, so it's pretty stupid.
It's my job to expand on
those stupid ideas.
Business Boy Kenichi will be in danger at the next serialization meeting.
I've got no choice but to bet
it all on Hirameki Tanto!
How many times do I have to tell you not to do it this way?
Y-You don't have
to say it so violently.
I'm the teacher here!
Don't complain!
I told you not to show
upskirt in weird ways!
It doesn't fit your manga!
All you need to do is show normal stuff, like changing clothes and bathing!
That's why I put in a changing
scene right before a bath!
Why would you see up
someone's skirt from a low angle
while they're changing for a bath?
That's weird!
Even if you don't have a knack for this, you should be able to see that!
Are you following me?
Here, you should either show
the panties at her ankles,
or from an upwards view as
she takes them off her legs!
That's how to express
getting changed for a bath!
Please hold on, I'm taking notes.
Just memorize it!
You're going to a good
college, aren't you?
Shut up!
My college has
nothing to do with this!
And why is she lost in thought
while washing herself?
That doesn't happen!
It's a girl washing herself.
Shouldn't that make guys happy?
In these kinds of scenes, she'd usually be in the bathtub already!
Do you lose yourself in thought while scrubbing your ass?!
Ass?
Please watch your language!
Ah, sorry.
While scrubbing your butt—
Hey, that's the same thing!
No, it's pretty different!
Um, while washing your ass...
No, bathtub, bathtub...
Listen, fix the parts I pointed
out to you by tomorrow.
What? That's impossible!
In an hour, it'll already be tomorrow!
You're aiming to
get serialized, right?
You'd better draw all night!
Don't say lack of sleep is bad for your skin, or something.
I won't.
I'll do my best.
Good girl.
Aoki Ko.
A mysterious author.
She seems like a different
person with each manuscript.
Yeah, really.
It's becoming more and
more like a shounen manga.
Did she hire someone to help her?
Maybe.
A college friend, perhaps?
What do you think?
Since it's gotten this good,
I'm thinking of submitting it to the serialization committee instead of doing a one-shot.
Yeah.
If she can make three
chapters that are this good.
All right!
Wow, I can't believe things are going this well for me, even though it's only my first year!
Huh?
Aoki's, too?
Yeah.
It looks like her manuscript's gonna be submitted to the serialization committee.
I coached her on panty shots.
She'll be a formidable enemy!
Of course, the best thing would be for you both to get serialized.
Don't lose.
Go for it!
Master Niizuma and I are waiting.
Okay.
We'll definitely score
a serialization this time!
I never thought Aoki
would be in the mix, too.
Fukuda must really be something.
It's fine! I'm kinda fired up now!
I feel kinda bad for Miura,
It'll feel even better
when we get serialized,
since we're up against
such a formidable rival!
Yeah!
Right, let's go for it!
Tomorrow's the big day.
Yes.
I believe it's all thanks to you
that I've made it to the
serialization committee.
Thank you.
It's too early for thanks.
The real challenge comes
after you get serialized.
I know.
My editor told me that I need
more practice with drawing people.
Yeah,
because your art kinda sucks.
It's not as bad as yours, though.
Oh, now you've done it.
My editor told me to aim
to be better than Ashirogi...
but I have mixed feelings about that.
They're friends, as well as rivals.
Isn't that what we always say?
I told Ashirogi not to lose to you.
I'll say the same to you.
Don't lose to them!
Do your best.
Okay.
I will.
What's this?
We've got this many editors,
but they could only scrape
together eight names?
I'll tell the lead editors
to encourage them.
Oh, excuse me.
May I see the comments on the names?
Let's see.
Ashirogi's, where's Ashirogi's?
Oh, there it is.
Huh?
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
Next
Episode
Tanto's serialization will
be decided in this committee!
I'm worried about Nakai, too.
I wonder what'll happen
with Takahama's serialization.
Everyone's at a crucial moment!
Next time on Bakuman:
Special Relationship
and Hometown
Special Relationship and Hometown.
Even if your dream's been
shattered, never give up!