Call Ended
I think Azuki just dumped me!
She found out that I've been hiding what happened between her mom and my uncle...
and told me she couldn't trust me.
That's not good.
Unlike Miyoshi, Azuki isn't
the type to forgive cheating.
I didn't cheat!
W-Well, yeah...
but this is bad.
Yeah, for now, I'd better apologize.
H-Hi, this is Mashiro.
Yes?
I'm sorry about before.
But I haven't done anything
wrong, so please trust me.
I do trust you.
So just tell me.
Well, um—
If you trust me, I shouldn't
have to tell you...
If no one's done anything wrong, you should be able to talk about it.
I can only think you're
covering for Takagi.
But when you were worried about doing that photo book,
you hid it from me.
I think hiding something
to avoid worrying others
and hiding something you did wrong are two different things.
But I already told you I
didn't do anything wrong!
How come you get to decide?
If nothing's wrong, you
should be able to tell me.
You don't trust me!
You don't trust me enough to tell me!
I've had enough!
That's my line!
I can't do it.
I'm pissed now.
In the end, neither Azuki
nor Miyoshi trusts us.
Even though we haven't
done anything wrong.
If Saiko and Azuki break up
because of something I did...
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Monkeys and Marriage
This won't work.
Let's just tell them everything!
What about Aoki?
Will Miyoshi accept that?
First, I'll stop exchanging
ideas with Aoki.
I'll tell her afterwards and
promise never to do it again.
And that thing with Iwase
was just a misunderstanding.
If there's nothing left to hide, then you and Azuki can make up.
I'll ask Aoki.
Hello, this is Aoki.
H-Hello.
You seem quite cheerful today.
Ah, I'm sorry.
You're the only man
I can trust right now,
so honestly, I enjoy talking with you.
You enjoy it?!
Talking with me?
Yes.
This is the first time
I've been able to be honest
and talk freely with a man.
Thank you for everything.
I look forward to
continuing our relationship
as mangakas and occasional rivals.
S-Sorry.
I couldn't tell her I wanted
to stop talking with her.
Well, she didn't do anything wrong.
Shouldn't you just tell
Azuki everything?
She'll just tell Miyoshi.
And if I tell her not to,
she'll just get even angrier.
Yeah.
Whatever.
Let's just wait it out and
see how it goes for a while.
But I've caused
trouble for both of you...
If they apologize,
then we can tell them everything.
Otherwise, they'll walk
all over us in the future!
Now!
Let's get started on that serialization
name for when Tanto gets first place!
Y-Yeah.
"If they apologize..."
This is bad.
Saiko's really stubborn when
it comes to things like this.
What?!
You called him?
No luck with either Takagi or Mashiro.
They're both hiding something.
Both of them?
You talked to Mashiro?
Yeah.
We got into a fight.
A fight?
Miho and Mashiro had a fight?
I can't believe he'd
hide something from me.
That's unforgivable, right?
Huh?
Yeah...
Crap.
It's our fault...
What should I do?
Miho's stubborn when it
comes to things like this...
Well, Mashiro too.
Rice Balls
Yen
All
It usually comes on release day...
An email from Azuki
about her impressions.
What else...
Hey!
How about you stop being stubborn and tell Azuki everything?
Let it go already.
I won't be the one to fold first.
Anyways, let's get to the office.
O-Okay.
Thursday, August 23rd
It's gonna be a while before we find out Next's final rankings...
I should have asked him
to tell us the early results.
Tanto...
can get first place, right?
It's not "can", it's "will."
I think it'll go over
well with little kids,
but Next has a higher
readership age than Jack does.
Saiko, you're just useless without Azuki's "It was great!" email.
That's not true!
I'll be waiting downstairs.
Okay.
Thursday, August 30th
That's him!
Tanto took 1st place
in the final rankings!
We did it!
This is the first time
we've gotten 1st place!
I'm so happy!
Damn! It's the first time one of my edited works has gotten 1st too!
Let's ride this momentum all the way to the next serialization meeting!
Yes!
We'll do our best!
We did it!
I didn't know I'd be this happy about getting 1st in the final rankings.
Next time, let's get 1st in Jack!
Yeah...
What's wrong, Saiko?
I'll try telling Azuki.
Right!
Oh, Yamahisa.
Time of Blue Leaves got 2nd.
I think it did well, considering
it was up against Ashirogi.
2nd is just fine for getting serialized.
It didn't get to have the first
few pages in color, after all.
I wonder if that's all it was?
Yamahisa.
Yes?
Time of Blue Leaves did well with older males and females.
That was pretty much
what we were aiming for.
It's been a while since I've
seen a romance like this.
It'll work!
You really think so?!
Yeah, if we do something about the art.
So that was the issue, after all.
I was concerned about it too.
If Aoki is fine with
drawing the faces alone,
you could try pairing her
up with Nakai Takuro again,
with him as the artist
and her as the author.
This time, in the magazine itself.
I understand.
I'll try to push her
to pair up with Nakai again.
I won't lose to Tanto like this again!
I'm counting on you.
If it goes well, it could
get a drama adaptation!
She could have said
"Congratulations", at least...
Maybe she's working really late?
I guess she won't
reply unless I apologize.
Don't you think she's
taking things too far?
Oh, that's mine.
Congratulations on
getting first place!
Oh, thank you.
I was second.
Second?
That's great!
You don't mind if I
congratulate you, right?
I am frustrated,
but...
I'm glad that Ashirogi,
whom I collaborated
with, was number one.
Let's both work hard
from here on out.
Yes, thank you!
Talk to you later.
Why am I so happy?
Even though I only
got second place?
Do I like...?
No, I can't feel that way.
He has a girlfriend.
This is Yamahisa from Jack.
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
H-Hello.
This may be sudden, but we decided to try out Time of Blue Leaves
as a one-shot in Jack!
Really?
Yep!
If we can have Nakai do the art.
The general consensus in the editing department is that it would be for the best.
Nakai and a fellow female assistant?
Yes.
So I don't think you need
to worry about him anymore.
I don't have the right to criticize Nakai now.
Aoki?
I understand.
If it will improve the manga,
I'll trust you and do as you say.
Okay!
Then I'll follow up
with Nakai immediately.
No.
I will speak with him directly.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Um, what was it you
wanted to talk about?
I was wondering if you
would draw for me again.
Time of Blue Leaves, which
was published in Next...
is going to be tried out
as a one-shot in Jack.
I love you!
I didn't think it was possible,
but could that character in Time of Blue Leaves really have been...
Being popular sure is tough.
My editor suggested that
you should do the art.
I'll be brief, since I slipped out of work to come talk to you.
Okay.
You see,
I'm enjoying my current job, and I'm getting along well with Katou Natsumi,
a fellow assistant.
I'm having trouble deciding
between you two.
I don't really understand...
If you want to work
with me, go out with me.
That's my condition.
Nakai.
Yes?
Wow.
That stuff actually happens?
You're horrible!
Dating as a requirement
for working together?
As a man...
as a person... you're awful!
I see.
I'm relieved.
Since you've gone this far, my doubts have all been cleared up.
Natsumi is waiting for me, so...
Goodbye.
For the first chapter, we'll go with "The gum that makes you say cool stuff"
and "The cast on your arm that punches back."
Which of these inventions do you want to use for chapters two and up?
He hasn't sent Azuki any mail since then.
This is getting bad.
We have to get this serialized,
make it into a big hit,
and then we'll get an anime...
I can't even email her until then?
Actually, is our promise to
get married once I get an anime
even valid at this point?
Hey, you alive?
Saiko?
What?
I'll go home for today
and think about it.
Here's the list of inventions.
Number them in the order
of which ones you like most.
If he's like that,
it'll affect our work.
This isn't the time
to be stubborn.
What's wrong?
Even though you've
finally come to visit,
you've been looking
down this whole time.
I'm sorry for staying over so long.
I don't mind.
It's like I have more
daughters now; It's kind of fun.
I fought with my friend.
Your friend...
Is it a boy?
Well, yeah.
Hey, what's going on
with Miho and Mashiro?
She doesn't tell me anything,
so give me the details before
she gets back from work!
Th-The details?
Excuse me for a minute.
I'm saved.
Takagi?
Takagi Akito
You Have New Mail
No Subject
If you are still at Azuki's house,
move to a place where she won't hear you.
What's this?
What's with that attitude?
A friend?
Y-Yeah.
I need to go make a call.
See you later!
I won't wait 30 minutes!
Oh, Miyoshi.
That was fast.
What's with the "Oh?"
You guys are idiots!
What was with that manga?
Huh?
You didn't like Tanto?
It got 1st place, though...
Not that one!
The one that used Miho
and Mashiro's romance!
What are you doing,
telling everybody about it?!
Oh, that.
"That?"!
You're so obviously prattling away with both Iwase and that female mangaka!
Are the two of you going on group dates with both of them every day, or something?
Sounds like fun!
Even though you never take
me out on a proper date,
you're really chummy
with pretty girls!
You should only do stuff like that after you break up with me—
Shut up!
Be quiet for a minute!
Just come back already.
I can't stand
that Azuki and Mashiro ended
up like this because of us.
I feel the same way, but...
It's because of you, not because of us.
All right, I get it.
Anyways, I'm going
to explain it to you,
so just calm down and listen.
I can't get Nakai to do the art now.
What should I do?
I'm telling you, it was
a misunderstanding!
I told Iwase I liked you
1,000 times more than her.
I really did!
And how much more do
you like me than Aoki?
Three times?
Why are you being realistic there?
That's so stupid.
But since it's realistic, I'll believe you when you say you like me.
Yeah.
I like you more than anyone.
If you're going that far, then take me out on a date to the zoo.
Huh?
Why?
All right.
I'll explain everything
properly at the zoo.
Hmm, so you're really gonna make it up to me by taking me out on a fun date?
If I'm not satisfied, I'll
beat the crap out of you.
That'll be up to you.
But I really do like
you more than anyone.
I get it.
I'm coming now.
Okay.
See you at 3 at the
monkey mountain, then.
Why the monkey mountain?
Let's see...
Monkey mountain, monkey mountain.
I hope I can tell Miyoshi
apart from the monkeys.
Aoki?!
Takagi!
Wh-Why?
Could Miyoshi have arranged this?
No, she's not capable of that...
We meet again by coincidence.
At this time of all times.
Of all times?
I don't know what to do!
Wh-What's wrong?
She smells good...
Wait a minute,
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
Miyoshi!
You didn't have to go this far to show off to me! I get it already!
Wait! That's not it!
Th-That's my girlfriend!
Oh no!
Please wait!
I-I'm no one suspicious!
Suspicious?
You're super suspicious!
How can you say that when you were all over him, you temptress!
She wasn't all over me!
I just had my hand on her shoulder!
You should have just
kissed while you were at it!
That's what you wanted
me to see, right?!
Wait!
I hope you're happy together!
Takagi!
Miyoshi!
Shut up!
Leave me alone!
Marry me!
I love you more than anyone else!
Idiot.
You're just trying to keep hold of me by copying Mashiro.
I'm not copying him.
Let's do it now.
Marry me right now.
R-Right now?
I'm 19, and you're still 18!
We can legally marry!
But we're still college students!
I think it's a wonderful thing for college students to marry.
You think it's wonderful?
Who the hell are you, anyway?
I thought he was
cheating with Iwase.
I'm Aoki Yuriko.
I was serialized in Shounen Jack under the name Aoki Ko.
I know that,
but you two were
hugging back there.
Since you drew a manga like that, you and Takagi must be real close, huh?
Well, that's...
I won't deny that.
I thought so!
No, we just talked about manga!
While hugging?
There's a really good
explanation for that...
There is, right?
No, I don't have a reasonable justification for hugging you.
You don't?!
I get the overall picture.
This isn't a manga.
Would you really meet at
the zoo by coincidence twice?
And on top of that, Aoki
was troubled both times?
Well, that's what happened.
I'm really sorry.
I won't call him anymore,
and I won't talk to him if we
meet by coincidence again.
Sorry for all this.
So trust Takagi and marry him!
He proposed on a whim just
to stop me from running off.
No, if you say yes, then I'll do it.
If we're always together,
there won't be any more
misunderstandings like this.
I would have preferred to do it after becoming a famous mangaka,
but if you're willing to
struggle with me, then...
I think it's wonderful
for people to struggle together
and form a strong bond.
You guys say some nice things.
B-But there's stuff
like the ceremony and my parents' permission to worry about...
Oh, right.
I have to ask for your
hand in marriage and stuff.
Do you think I'd get permission?
I mean, I'll do my best!
Then let's get married
when you get serialized.
It's decided.
O-Okay.
Congratulations!
But you'll be busy
when that happens,
so we'll just get registered.
We'll have a ceremony when we can.
Right!
Please let me know
when that happens.
Oh, sorry.
I will support you from behind the scenes.
I just said I wouldn't talk
to Takagi anymore...
But Takagi's the only man you can trust and consult, right?
I've never...
had a person I could
get along with
like Takagi.
I'm sorry.
I think I was starting to like him.
Why did you have to
be so honest about that?
You should have stuck with the
"We're just fellow mangakas" story.
Yeah.
But Takagi and Nakai are both idiots.
If I were a man, I'd
definitely choose you.
I can still change my mind...
Takagi!
What are you saying in front of the girl you just proposed to?!
I'll think less of you!
No.
That was just one of his jokes.
Oh, okay.
Sorry.
Aoki, please continue
talking to Takagi.
In exchange,
I want you to become
friends with me too!
I-I'm very happy.
Thank you.
What?
Um, well,
I was just wondering if Azuki
will be satisfied with this.
Yeah, probably.
I can't trust you,
but I can trust Aoki.
What's with that?
That was a joke too...
right?
Well, I wouldn't know about that!
Miyoshi!
Miyoshi?
If I don't apologize,
our relationship
might end like this!
But Azuki should trust me more...
It's no good!
I can't make any progress at all.
Azuki!
Crap!
This might be a break-up email!
If it was going to come
to this, I should have...
Aoki
It's hard for me to forgive you for hiding that he was exchanging opinions with
Aoki. But I will forgive you. Aoki is a nice person. We became friends (lol)
Huh?
What's this?
Family Restaurant
Hachiouji
If anyone saw this, they'd think "Who does this guy think he is?"
He's got three beautiful
girls around him.
Two beautiful girls, you mean.
He's picking on you, Miho.
Oh, a reply from Mashiro?
What does it say?
"Huh? I don't get it."
Figures.
I should tell him the four
of us are having tea.
He'll get even more confused.
Yeah.
Huh?
The four of them?
I see, so Shuujin...
Even though he said he
was headed home for today.
Hey, Saiko.
Don't "Hey" me!
What are you doing leaving me out?
Sorry.
But you're mailing each
other again, right?
Y-Yeah.
You'd better be grateful.
Because of you,
I was forced to agree to marry
Miyoshi when we get serialized.
M-Marriage?!
What do you mean by "forced?!"
Ow!
Miyoshi!
But Kaya looks happy.
Shuujin.
Let's get serialized for sure
and make a popular manga!
Yeah!
When it gets an anime,
you'll get married too!
Yeah!
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
Next
Episode
I'll work hard and
aim for a serialization.
We're going to get married!
But will it go well?
It'll work out somehow!
Next time on Bakuman:
Prince and
Savior
The King and the Savior.
Is there anyone who will lend me a hand in accomplishing my dream?