kichi
jo
ji
Station
Are you guys seriously
going on hiatus?
Mashiro is drawing with no
intention of going on hiatus.
You saw him in the hospital, right?
Mashiro probably won't be happy if all of you go on hiatus for Trap's sake.
Yeah, probably not.
He might even blame himself.
That's why we're not
telling him about this.
Anyway, if the Chief Editor doesn't go back on his decision about putting Trap on hiatus,
we'll also put our four manga on hiatus.
That's what we've decided!
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Recall and Call
How long will this hiatus last?
Until Jack prints Trap again, of course!
No objections.
How will you be able to keep your assistants until that happens?
You won't be able to
continue paying them, right?
T-That's true...
I don't have enough to
keep paying them until April.
I'll take care of that.
I've got tons of money
and nothing to spend it on.
I'm glad it can come in handy.
That's what happens when someone sells 8.5 million copies over ten volumes.
Then I'll ask you this:
How much do you
want him to back down?
I am also dissatisfied
with a hiatus until April.
If the Chief Editor said that the hiatus
will only last until Mashiro
gets out of the hospital,
would you resume drawing?
Whether it's April or until he's discharged,
we won't draw until Trap
appears in Jack again.
Hiramaru, you're just
being an opportunist here.
Shut up.
W-What?!
We've all united together because we resent the steps the Chief Editor's taken.
It's not that I don't
want to draw manga...
Liar.
Well, how about it?
I won't go for that.
If you're going to lay out conditions, persuade the Chief Editor first.
Looks like they're committed to this.
So, if the hiatus looks like
it will last for many months,
we will simply move to another magazine.
Should we say that yet?
D-Don't be ridiculous!
We'll all be fired!
Is that so?
Well, Yuujirou's been
doing a good job for me...
Then I'll just keep going
and let my manga pile up.
I want to keep drawing, you see.
Please do so.
Nakai, Aoki, do you get it?
For Hideout, going on hiatus
won't work the same way
as it does for a popular
manga such as Crow.
You might be discontinued
if you take this chance.
T-That'll be bad...
I don't mind.
I would rather willingly cancel our manga
than deal with a Chief Editor who makes such unjust decisions.
I believe that he's wrong.
Yeah! Miss Aoki is the best!
Bravo! Bravo!
I like you, Aoki.
I'm telling you...!
There's no point in talking
here with just the editors.
We'll go to the Chief
Editor and let him have it.
Yes!
Let's tell him clearly
that we're taking a break.
Hey, wait!
We'll talk this over
with the Chief Editor,
but you guys shouldn't come along.
Why?
It'll get complicated.
Like that huge mess with Koogy.
Why can't they come with us?
I don't agree with the Chief
Editor on this one, either.
Also, I have a hard time imagining these two quitting their boycott anytime soon.
Of course not!
Yuujirou is a reasonable man.
Even so, you'd better continue drawing your manuscripts.
The Chief Editor may take back his decisions about Trap at any time.
Roger!
I know.
Wha...?
Hiramaru, you also need to keep drawing.
Got it?
W-Well, of course!
How could you think
I wouldn't, Yoshida-shi?
Chief, may we have a word with you?
What is so important that my two lead editors need to speak with me?
Niizuma Eiji, Hiramaru Kazuya,
Fukuda Shinta, and the team of Aoki Ko and Nakai Takuro...
in protest against your decision,
have declared that
they will also go on hiatus
for the duration of the time
that Trap is on hiatus.
In other words, this is a boycott?
Yes.
Of course, we'll keep
trying to convince them.
However, they are
resolved in their decision.
At this point, they
definitely will go on hiatus.
If the manuscripts fail to
make their deadlines,
that is the responsibility
of the supervising editor,
and therefore, it becomes my responsibility as Chief Editor.
Well, again, if you remove the hiatus on Trap, the four manga will resume—
Trap's hiatus is a settled matter.
Put forth your best efforts to see
that those four manga's manuscripts continue to come in.
That is all I have to say.
But Chief...
This is something I
have already decided.
Chief!
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
Don't worry, Mom.
I know my own body best.
You never listen to me!
Good afternoon!
Miura!
Hi!
How are you feeling?
The Chief Editor said he won't print Trap even if I keep drawing,
but I won't give up
until the very end.
I'll finish it by Friday like always!
I get it. I get it.
If the manuscript gets finished,
I'll come and pick it up.
After his surgery, if he properly
finishes his manuscripts,
the Chief Editor might re-think his decision
and resume printing earlier
than he said he would!
Y-Yeah.
Won't you at least make the hiatus only until Mashiro gets better...
instead of until Ashirogi Muto graduate from high school?
If you do that, then it may be possible to convince Niizuma and the others—
Don't make me repeat myself.
What are you doing?
Make sure your authors do not let their manuscripts fall behind.
Shuujin.
Sorry, but can you come
by early tomorrow
to take the manuscript to our office?
Mashiro, take it easy...
I know.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I should be trying to stop him...
No. I know full well
that he won't stop.
He's stubborn, just like his father.
I shouldn't tell him about the boycott.
He'll just blame himself.
Come in.
Hello.
Miho!
Then I'll come by on Friday
to get the manuscript.
Yes, please do.
I'll go home, then.
I have to make dinner
for your grandpa.
Well, let's go, Miyoshi.
Oh, right.
You can stay, Kaya. Takagi, too.
What are you saying?
We'll let you have some
time alone together.
Kiss him!
Kiss~!
See ya!
Oh, Kaya...
My surgery's been scheduled
for this coming Monday.
I see.
Mashiro.
Charm
Here.
I'm worried about your surgery, after all.
Thanks.
On the day of your surgery,
I'll skip school and come here.
You don't have to do that.
It's a surgery with a
99% rate of success.
Huh?
What about the 1%?
I'm definitely coming.
It'll be okay, right?
Yeah.
We're high school seniors, aren't we?
Um, why are you saying
something so obvious?
Kaya just said...
Kiss him! Kiss~!
C-Could she...!?
A-Azuki,
because I have a 1% chance of dying, are you going to...?
Huh?
What are you saying?
I don't think you'll die.
Why did you say that?
S-Sorry!
I mean that I could die
without having kissed—
That's not it.
I wonder if I'm being strange.
I don't think I want to kiss you.
Oh, not like that.
I've never felt like I've wanted to.
I think I understand.
Really?
When I'm with you, it's like the inside of my head goes blank,
so I'm not thinking about that at all.
It's like, I'm just happy
that we're together.
I'm glad.
I feel that way too.
Is that really for the best?
I feel like I'm not treating you right.
It's fine.
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
I'm leaving him in your care, Doctor.
He'll be fine, ma'am.
Please don't worry so much.
Yes.
Don't make that face, Miyoshi.
I'm the one who should be nervous.
Yeah...
Would friends and family
please wait in another room?
Oh, yeah.
Well, I'm going in.
Good luck, Mashiro.
Even you're worried.
I'll be fine.
I have your good luck charm.
Roll him in.
Okay.
Yakusa Municipal Hospital
I'm glad your surgery went well.
Yes, I can leave the hospital soon.
Don't push yourself.
I have a present for you two today.
The first volume of
Shady Detective Trap!
It just got delivered today.
A-Awesome!
You're the culprit.
It's like a real manga!
It is a real manga!
This'll be lined up in stores
all over the country, right?
Of course!
Aren't you Mr. Obvious today.
It's no good.
I can't read it with tears in my eyes.
Saiko, let's hurry up
and resume serialization!
Yeah!
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
You're just being stubborn
about handing it over.
Are you okay with betraying
your readers like that?!
I apologize, but it's already settled.
Hail boycotting!
So you won't change your mind, then.
Of course not.
So you'd better change
the Chief Editor's mind.
I truly apologize.
Please wait a bit.
Chief.
What?
The printing office
won't wait any longer.
Shounen Jack
I know it's not in there, but I won't believe it until I see it.
Yeah.
It's kinda lonely.
Hm?
Huh?
What?
It's not just Trap!
Crow, Kiyoshi, Otters, and
Hideout Door aren't in here either!
W-Why?!
Miura, what's all this about?!
Since Trap has been forced to go on hiatus, they are also boycotting.
The reason put here for us
is "Due to sudden illness",
but the reason put for them is "Due to circumstances of the author".
Isn't it going to be a big problem if Jack gets published like this?
All the works published in Weekly Shounen Jack are fiction. There is
absolutely no relation to any actual persons, organizations or events.
※Due to the author's sudden illness. Shady Detective Trap is on hiatus.
※Due to the authors circumstances, Crow, Kiyoshi Knight, Otters 11
and Hideout Door are on hiatus.
Oh, all you authors are awesome!
Ekoda Realtor
Can't wait to see what
happens on Monday.
Really awesome!
In any case, we've taken
a break for one week.
I'll use that time to draw
an even better manuscript.
Well, now I can rest for a week.
You're the one who seems to be the happiest about the hiatus, Hiramaru.
Fukuda and the rest have said
that they will go on hiatus until Trap is printed in Jack again.
That's what they're demanding.
I...
I won't have that!
It's not right for everyone to have to take a break for our sake!
Right!
Mashiro, if you get too
excited, your stitches will...
Most importantly, the readers...
What about the readers who look forward to those manga every week?!
I understand how you feel.
So I have some advice for you:
Will you accept a hiatus
until you're discharged?
W-Why are you even
talking about that?
Chapters 20 and 21 are ready!
I'll even have chapter
22 done by Monday!
I know, but...
If we can convince the
Chief Editor with that condition,
Fukuda and the rest
may stop boycotting,
because they are the most upset about
you having to go on
hiatus until you graduate.
I don't want them to
have to stay on hiatus.
If that's the only way...
I'm very sorry. In regard to that matter,
This is Jack's Editing Department.
as explained in the publication
I'm sorry. Regarding your inquiry of the hiatuses this week...
Monday, July 11th
Jack Issue 33 Goes on Sale
it is due to authors' circumstances...
Well, of course this would happen.
Jack has five titles on hiatus.
It would even make the news.
Akira! Yuujirou!
Why are you just sitting
there and chatting?!
Answer the phones!
The phones were off
the hook this morning.
Things calmed down
a bit in the afternoon.
I see.
If this mass hiatus continues next week, it'll be an even bigger problem.
You may not be able to accept it, but...
Miura.
Can you call Fukuda and Niizuma here?
Don't give me that shit!
If they've finished, then just knock them down and grab the manuscripts!
That's an old-fashioned way of thinking.
Listen up!
If next week's issue still has
those four manga on hiatus,
prepare to be fired!
It's not just you.
The Chief Editor's
head may roll for this!
Well, it's not like we can just...
I will try to obtain it.
Incoming call           Miura Gorou
Refuse        Accept       Forward
Miura's calling me, so
I'm heading out for a bit.
Aren't I more important than Miura?
Yes, in terms of office hierarchy.
Kitashita Juuichi
Mashiro Moritaka
Please stop your boycott.
We're fine with a hiatus
until I'm discharged.
Are you really fine with that?
We don't have a choice.
I don't want to, but it's
my fault for getting sick.
Ashirogi themselves are saying it.
You should end this.
Wait a minute.
Do we have your guarantee
that if we stop the boycott,
Trap will resume as soon as he gets discharged from the hospital?
Er, not yet.
What's with that?
If Ashirogi is okay with
that, then I am too.
Really?
Then I'll put my neck on the line to convince the Chief Editor.
I didn't agree with him
on this in the first place.
I don't really care about
your neck, though.
All right! Fine!
But if Trap isn't resumed after all this,
I'll really lose it and
wring your neck myself!
Y-Yeah!
That's how it is, Hiramaru.
Hiramaru Kazuya
No Mr.Yoshida
No
Soliciting
I-I'm so glad.
The readers are waiting for Otters...
Weekly Shounen Jack
Title: Kiyoshi Knight
Good job on convincing them.
However, Trap will only resume after Ashirogi Muto graduate from high school.
Chief!
Yuujirou, don't get so fired up!
We still have time...
It's not something that'll
be resolved with more time!
I will send Crow and
Kiyoshi to the press.
What should I do?
I want to get their serialization resumed as quickly as possible.
They really are serious.
What can I do for them as their editor?
Weekly Shounen Jack
Title: Shady Detective Trap #23
It got announced, huh?
Yeah, but that was planned
over six months ago.
And our second volume has been postponed until after we resume.
Niizuma Eiji
Don't take the easy road!
Congrats  Anime Adaptation!!!
He got ahead of us again.
Has the Chief Editor
still not agreed yet?
N-No...
That's not fair, since they already agreed to stop the boycott.
I'm sorry.
Chapter 25 is finished.
A-All right.
I'll look at it right now.
Amazing.
The quality hasn't dropped at all since he's been in the hospital.
On the contrary, it's improved!
Trap really is good!
Even so...
But you know,
at this rate, they'll have stopped boycotting for no reason!
Which means that if it isn't resumed once he gets out, then Fukuda really will go crazy.
He's kept up with his
manuscripts, though.
Mashiro's working hard.
By September, we'll have about 10 unpublished chapters.
No matter how many we'll have, all we can do now is make manga.
That's it!
I don't know if it'll work,
but it's definitely worth trying!
We don't talk much, do we?
If our dreams come true
and we g-get married...
it might still be like this.
Probably.
"Probably"?
Even if we stop being so shy, we're just normally quiet people.
Does that sound okay to you?
Yeah, it's fine.
I think so too.
What's most important now
is to keep working hard,
without giving up.
September 15th
Congrats on your discharge!
Sorry for worrying you.
Then, let's go.
Yes!
Finally, huh?
Sorry, Mom.
I'll be heading to the editorial department before going home...
Oh, it's fine. I understand.
Go on.
Then, I'll be going.
Yeah.
I am also dissatisfied
with a hiatus until April.
It's not something that'll be resolved with more time!
An editor's job is to receive the manuscript from the authors...
and to make sure it's put on the page.
Weekly Shounen Jack
Title:      Shady Detective Trap #24
Title:      Shady Detective Trap #30
These are the manuscripts
he drew while in the hospital.
One per week.
He handed them in one by
one without a drop in quality.
On the contrary, they got even better!
I have 11 chapters here.
Which means that if you
start publishing them now,
they'll last until the end of the year!
Mashiro has also made
a complete recovery.
More than anything, the fact that he drew all of these while in the hospital...
proves his strength
to continue serializing!
While you set all this up,
did you stop to think about what you would have done in the worst case scenario?
I refused to let anyone stop me!
I also went along with it!
M-My uncle
Kawaguchi Tarou said;
That until you get serialized, it's about "conceit, effort, and luck".
Once you've managed to get serialized,
it's "physical strength, emotional strength, and finally, guts!"
Kawaguchi Tarou read
too many sports manga.
Fine.
I will gladly accept your
"gutsy" manuscripts.
I will resume Trap
as quickly as possible!
Thank you!
Thank god...
We did it!
Those three really did it.
Guts, of all things...
Is this the 80's, or something?
Miura.
Th-This is the same thing you did before the serialization meeting...
Takagi, Mashiro.
Yes?
You pushed it way too far!
S-Sorry.
You did well.
You tried really hard!
Receiving E-Mail
Mashiro Moritaka
Trap resumes!
We start back up in issue 45
on Oct 3rd with our color spread!
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
I can finally draw manga again!
Next
Episode
Aoki and I won't lose, either!
But being a pro is really tough.
Next time on Bakuman:
Resumption and
Low-Rank
"Resumption and Low-Rank."
I had a dream about
going on a date with Aoki!