I'm home.
Welcome back.
You were out late today.
Your dad's worried about you.
I'm sorry.
Dinner's all set.
All right.
What's wrong, Miho?
Did something happen?
No, not really.
I see.
I'll go change.
You're going to waste a chance like that?
I apologize.
Even for popular voice actresses, opportunities for photo books don't pop up too often.
But doing that kind of work before I become popular as a voice actress—
You want to be more popular, don't you?
Think of this as a stepping stone towards that.
If you really want to be a voice actress, you can do that after you get as popular as an idol!
I don't want to do another thing like the "St. Visual's Girls Academy" ending...
St. Visual's Girls Academy New ED song "Symphony Right Before Dawn"
The three popular characters form a group!!
Song Sac-Vis Female Choir Club: Underclassmen Group
St. Visual's Girls Academy New ED song "Symphony Right Before Dawn"
The three popular characters form a group!!
Song Sac-Vis Female Choir Club: Underclassmen Group
That was a huge success.
Even with your lousy singing voice, you've got such good offers coming in!
Listen, if you refuse an offer like this, it'll be very hard to make a living as a voice actress!
The world isn't that easy!
I'm sorry. Please let me think about it.
Geez...
I'm at the Jack New Year's party. I want to take
the top spot and grant your dream one day!
yume kanaeru made chousen wa tsuzuku
The fight doesn't end until I fulfill my dream
boku wa dokomade chikazuketandarou?
I wonder how far I've come now?
juunengo no mirai kagayaiteru sugata wa
In ten years, I'll be living the dream
koukai wa shinai jibun de egaita story
It's the scenario I wrote for myself, so I'll have no regrets
fumidaseba yukute habamu genjitsu
But life isn't that easy, and it's full of obstacles
makenai to ima mune ni chikatta
Still, I swear to myself that I won't ever back down
kokorozashita tsukamitai yume ga arukara
I have a dream that I absolutely want to achieve
moyashite yuke jounetsu wo atsuku
So I fuel my passion until I succeed
yume no tochuu de meguriau deai to wakare
There will be meetings and partings along the way
kimi ga oshietekureta boku dake ga motsu chikara
But I'll simply believe in my strength that you've taught me
tachiagatteikundayo nando tsumazuitatte
And rise back up again and again and again
Dream of Life
Anthologies and Photo Books
Assistant IN
Manuscript #1 UP
Manuscript #2 UP
Once again...
Silence
The atmosphere
is unbearable.
You've been in a huff for two weeks!
It's painstaking work.
Yeah!
You've got to be on your best behavior.
I know, I know.
Well? Is that girl assistant cute?
Not as cute as you, so don't worry.
Are you saying that if she was,
I would need to worry?
No!
I'm not sure if the atmosphere will change just because I invited Miyoshi over.
I need to do something...
But I've already tried turning
on the radio and the TV.
Is there anything else I can do?
I'm coming in!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Um, this may be sudden, but this is my classmate and the person I'm going out with...
I'm Miyoshi Kaya.
Nice to meet you!
I'm Kato. Nice to meet you.
I'm Ogawa. Pleased to meet you.
And the one working in the middle is Takahama.
It's so nice to meet you!
Ogawa, sorry to interrupt,
but she can do inking at least.
Feel free to give me work to do!
Well then, I can show you
what needs to be done.
If you teach me, I can do anything you need!
Use me for other tasks too!
It's like it just became more suffocating having another person in here.
Silence
Isn't it too quiet in here for six people?
That's my chief!
I know, right?
We have to, like, be more congenial!
Right, but I have no idea what to talk about.
Ogawa, do you have a girlfriend?
You have an adult appeal!
You're going to start out with a personal topic like that?!
I live with my girlfriend, and she's pregnant.
Living together, that's...!
Yeah. We're not getting married yet.
Wow, so adult!
Marriage...
That's why you have several jobs.
E-Mail
Message
Back
I have to pull in a decent income, you see.
When will the baby be born?
It's still a ways off.
Is it a boy or a girl?!
Not sure...
I'm heading home.
Me too.
Good work today.
I'll be counting on you tomorrow!
Good job, you two.
You too, Miyoshi.
Sorry for calling you over so suddenly.
I had fun drawing manga.
I was surprised at Ogawa though.
That's why he's assisting other authors too.
Others?
Yeah. Monday and Tuesday he assists the author of Shounen 3.
He's working hard since he's gonna be a daddy.
You're probably right.
You can go now too, Miyoshi.
There's nothing left to do.
Then show me your TV!
The one you won at the New Year's party!
We've got a meeting with our editor now.
Successful people sure are busy.
We're not successful yet.
I was surprised when he suddenly brought his girlfriend over.
Having another girl around was a bit relaxing.
Now that we've got more people,
I can give you more time
to work on your own project.
Ah, well...
I'm happy just being an assistant.
Don't say that. Just go for it.
Though I went to a technical school for manga,
ever since then, I've been told I have no talent for writing stories.
Really?
I can draw, but I can't write.
That's why I polished my skills as an assistant.
But I think it turned out well.
I can make a living.
I think you're great, Ogawa!
I can learn a lot from you.
Oh, really?
Yes!
Have you gotten used to your assistants?
Yes, somehow.
I see.
Then let's talk about your fourth chapter.
Yes!
Takagi, have you thought of a rival?
Well, I'm thinking of a detective who tries to arrest the protagonist,
like Zenigata from Lupin III...
But that isn't very shounen-like.
Oh, really?
Just having a rival makes everything more exciting!
Then why wait till the fourth chapter?
We should introduce him earlier—
I'm not going to touch the chapters that Hattori approved
and submitted to the serialization committee.
If you're kicked out by your
3rd chapter, it's his fault.
But you're going to start revising your story in the fourth chapter based on reviews of the previous ones.
So prepare two different names.
If the first does well, go with that plotline.
If it doesn't, then change it to option two for the next chapter.
"If it doesn't?"
Miura, what's your honest
opinion of chapter three?
Should I say it?
Yes!
I'll be blunt. Is that okay?
Please tell us.
If we're not brutally honest with each other, we can't call this a business meeting.
I think it's stiff.
Stiff?
But I also think it's the best one so far.
Which is it?
Well, how should I put this?
Once you have a popular manga, you can play around with it a bit,
but at the beginning, everyone is desperate.
They don't have any room to relax.
I like a bit more fluff.
But since you're bringing the story to a conclusion in the first three chapters,
you had no space to play around with it.
So that's why chapter three is the best.
Well, there's not much to change.
Hattori's diligence shines
through, and it's tightly done.
Perhaps too much so.
I'm still an underling, so I think the way he did it is correct.
But the manga changes slightly according to the preferences of the editor.
You're not being very clear.
So you think it can be popular?
So that serialization continues?
Since we're doing it, we
have to think it'll be a hit!
If the people making it don't think it's good, it definitely won't be!
And there will be people who enjoy our work!
Take pride in that, and it'll encourage you to make the story even better!
He's not a bad guy.
I don't think so either, but...
He's taking Trap seriously.
I'll make up two different names for chapter four like he suggested.
Yeah.
No email again today?
I'll ask Miyoshi tomorrow.
Thanks.
Azuki Miho
Nickname                    Amame
Future Dream
Voice Actress
Comment:
I won't say "goodbye."
Even when I'm a
middle schooler, even
when I become an adult,
the fact that  I was a member of Grade 6 Class 3 will never change.
Class 3
will never
change.
Akigusa Second Elementary School
Graduation Anthology
Class of 2005
You have until the end of the month to make a decision about the photo book.
Got it?
Miho?
Come to think of it, I haven't talked to her lately.
I see.
Okay, I'll call her tonight.
Alright, thanks.
I have to make myself useful as an author's assistant!
Anyways, I'm counting on you.
Okay! I'll take care of it!
Mashiro
What to do?
Should I warn him?
Sensei!
Yes?
I have a question.
Sorry, did I make a mistake?
Well, it's about the
effectiveness of this panel...
Oh, is it hard to understand?
It's hard to grasp the meaning of it.
How's it going, you two?
The last train's departing soon.
I'm done with today's work.
How about you, Takahama?
Do you have some left?
Sorry, Kato, but can you split the rest with him?
What? Is that alright?
Then I'll be going.
Is it really okay?
Yeah.
At the rate he works, he can handle the rest of it no problem.
I'll get tomorrow's work ready!
Please do.
We'll be leaving, then.
Have a good evening!
Good work today!
Takahama, you can go too.
I'll take what's left and finish it at home.
No, I'll finish up today's work.
Then I'll stay here a bit longer too.
I like Disney.
Huh?
I want to work at Disney.
Disney...?
Yes.
I think that if you aim to be a mangaka, you should dream big.
You're right.
I think so too.
But why did you bring that up all of a sudden?
I respect you for your work ethic,
working on a serialization
while still in high school.
But those two who just left are no good.
They're satisfied just being assistants.
I just don't get it.
Ogawa's taken assisting to another level, and since he's skilled, I can understand.
But Kato's satisfied with
herself just being an assistant.
There's no way we can understand each other.
That's why I want you to work hard, Sensei.
Oh, okay.
But you don't have to call me "Sensei."
Then I'll call you Mashiro.
Tell the other two that.
You should tell them yourself!
Yeah.
What kind of manga do you like?
I like Ashita no Joe!
Joe huh?
It's really cool.
A real "man's manga."
Yeah!
Really? You talked with Takahama?
It was interesting talking to him.
So much so I didn't
even finish inking!
That's fine.
It's also important to communicate.
I'm headed to our office now.
I want to finish up
before they get there.
After I'm done with the classroom chores, I'll head right over.
Okay!
I forgot to ask about Azuki.
Azuki, are you doing okay?
Text input
Even for me, it's too simple.
Send!
What's he doing?
Shh, he'll hear you.
Huh?
Azuki Miho
Re: It's me, Mashiro
Yes, I'm fine. (lol)
It's short!
But at least she responded.
You Have New Mail
Another?
I've been asked to make a photo book. Is that ok? It seems they want to take some sketchy pics (lol)
What do I say?
I actually don't want her to do it, but I don't want to tell her that flat out.
I think it's your decision to make, not mine.
Sending E-mail
You Have New Mail
If I'm going to do it, I want you to see me naked before then.(lol)
Naked?!
What're you talking about, Azuki?!
Wait a minute.
Would Azuki even joke about wanting me to see her naked?
What're you saying? Let's talk about this in person.
You Have New Mail
Because if you see me naked, I shouldn't have a problem with anyone else seeing me in a bathing suit (lol)
T-This isn't a joke!
You Have New Mail
Let's have a proper conversation about
this photo book, and our dreams!
Why doesn't she pick up?
And then Negishi suddenly started singing!
What's with that?
Negi's crazy.
I know, right?
And then—
Huh?
Isn't that guy...
your boyfriend's friend?
Miyoshi! Can I talk to you for a minute?!
Could it be a confession?!
No way! He'd have to fight for her!
Did you tell Saiko Azuki's address?
Yeah, he looked pretty scary.
What the hell is he doing?
And what about Azuki?
Huh?
Don't give me that!
You called her, right?
Miyoshi!
She said if she doesn't do this, she might not get any work as a voice actress.
She wasn't very happy.
Dammit.
Just what is going on?!
That's dangerous, Takagi!
Azuki's been suffering alone all this time!
Why didn't I realize it sooner?
She's been acting strange a lot too!
You're abandoning the
manuscript to go on a date?!
Shuuji...
It's our first serialized chapter!
You said "If my dream
comes true" a million times!
Why now?
I'll draw when I get back.
Don't screw with me!
How long do you think it takes
to get to Azuki's house?!
If you don't proceed with the manuscript. our assistants will have nothing to do!
She won't answer her phone.
Let me go!
Calm down!
What happened to her?
I'm going because I don't know what happened and I can't talk to her!
Hey!
Mashiro!
Miyoshi, call Azuki.
It's no good. I've been trying,
but she won't pick up.
How about the house line?
I'll try it.
But I think her mom will answer.
I'll do it.
Hello, this is Azuki.
Hi, this is Takagi, a classmate of Azuki's from middle school.
Oh, it's been a while.
Yes, it has.
Have you been well?
Uh, yes.
Actually, I have a favor to ask.
Miho?
I'm coming in.
Akigusa Second Elementary School
Graduation Anthology
Class of 2005
Miho, you've got a call from Takagi.
If you don't want to talk, answer the phone and tell them yourself.
Hello, Takagi?
I'm putting Miho on.
Okay.
Azuki?
I think you're listening, so I'll talk.
Saiko is heading to your house.
He's ignoring the manuscript he has to draw.
Is that okay with you?!
If you're fine with that, then I misjudged you.
The door is closing. Please be careful.
Sorry!
Azuki, are you okay?
I'm sorry!
Go back and draw the manga!
Takagi called my house.
I'm sorry for causing trouble for everyone!
I thought I didn't want to show you what I'm like when I'm depressed,
so I didn't answer my phone.
But it's even worse for you to stop drawing manga because of me.
I won't have it!
So hurry back and draw!
But Azuki, you're worried
about the photo book, right?
Yeah.
Then it's better for me to go
and talk to you in person...
Mashiro, just tell me one thing.
What?
Regardless of how it'll affect my career as a voice actress,
would you be happy if I made a photo book?
Or not?
No!
I'd want to see your photo book, but I wouldn't want other people to see it!
I'd want it all for myself!
Thanks for telling me.
I won't do it.
I think I should be doing something different with my career.
Akigusa Second Elementary School
Graduation Anthology
Class of 2005
Last night, I looked at our
elementary school yearbook.
I looked at where I wrote my dream for the future, a voice actress.
Your dream?
Yeah.
I knew there was a job called "voice actress", and I genuinely wanted to become one.
I want to preserve that feeling.
I'm the same, I think.
When I was in elementary school,
I admired mangakas,
and I sketched a ton of
manga in my school notebook.
But I gave up on it when
I learned the harsh reality of it.
Reality?
Yeah.
There was a person who tried too hard making manga, and died.
Knowing how that world works,
I realize that if I step into it,
my ideals and reality might
change and even be crushed.
But the road is the same for everyone.
And I think there are people
who will realize their
dreams without being crushed,
no matter what obstacle is in their way.
You're right.
I'll improve bit by bit.
Talking to you helped
me sort out my feelings.
I feel better now, so don't
worry and draw your manga.
Okay.
And from now on, lets talk about everything.
I'm sorry for being stubborn
and acting tough, even while I was crying.
That's right.
You're the one who said "Lets try hard and encourage each other."
If we don't talk, I can't encourage you.
Yeah.
Mashiro, let's go to the beach one day.
We can take lots of pictures!
Sure, one day.
It's a promise for when
our dreams come true.
I'll bring lunch.
Then that's a promise too.
Our dreams keep increasing.
But just talking about dreams doesn't make them a reality.
Yeah.
You seem okay now, so I'm gonna hang up.
Thanks, Mashiro.
Talk to you later.
Okay.
Mashiro!
I'm sorry for interrupting
your chance at a date, Saiko.
Sorry, Shuujin.
Just come back and pen-in the manuscript.
Miho making a photo book, huh.
Yeah, in the end, she refused.
Can she continue her voice actress work?
Yeah, she got another call to audition.
She sent me a email.
Me too.
And she asked me to
properly apologize to Takagi.
You were really fearsome that day.
I said I'm sorry.
It all went well after
that though, right?
Most importantly, Trap safely began its first serialization.
Yeah, it's finally begun.
Now we just have to wait and see how it does in the polls.
Yeah, a first chapter of a new series should get first place.
It's Miura.
He'll have the early results, won't he?
Probably.
I'm answering it.
Yes, this is Takagi.
kurikaesu nibuku detarame na sekai
In this world, every day is dull and full of nonsense
urusakute mimi wo fusaida
I cover my ears, trying to mute the noise
nan no tame ni kizutsukeatteiru no?
Why do people hurt each other?
Can you hear my heartbeat
Baby I trust you my friend
zetsubou ni fushita kokoro no sumi
In the contradictory, overlapping shadows
orikasanaru mujun no kage ni
on the recesses of my heart, fallen into despair
mune wo itamenagara
While carrying this pain in my chest,
ashita wo yume mireru no?
can I really dream of tomorrow?
toori ame no ato ni mitsuketa niji wo omotte
Remembering the rainbow I found after the rain,
me wo tojiru Fly with me donna nagai yume mo
I close my eyes; come fly with me into my dream
iroasenai kimi to nara
If I have you, who shines so strong
egakidaseru kienai niji mo
I can envision an everlasting rainbow
deaeta ano hi ni mita tsukiakari de sae mo
And even remember the moonlight of night we met
utsushidasu nando demo
I can picture them... countless times
nando demo
over and over again
Next
Episode
It's the start of Trap's serialization.
I'm worried about the ranking
and other things too...
I'll fix up any problems with my team!
Window
and Snow
Fukuda, let me call you "boss!"
Don't call me that!
Next time on Bakuman:
"Window and Snow."
Even if my body is freezing,
my dreams won't cool down!